CNSTNT=CNSTNT—is a real-number constant for U2DREL and U1DREL, and an integer constant for U2DINT. If the array is being defined as a constant, CNSTNT is the constant value. If individual elements of the array are being read, the values are multiplied by CNSTNT after they are read. When CNSTNT is used as a multiplier and specified as 0, it is changed to 1.
EXPLANATIONOFVARIABLES=Explanation of variables
FB_BODY=Enter value
FB_TO=rbwinst@usgs.gov
FB_TONOJS=rbwinst@usgs.gov
HELP_URL=http://water.usgs.gov/nrp/gwsoftware/modflow2000/MFDOC/index.html
MNWFILENAME=filename = is the name of an auxiliary output file.
NOTES=Notes
