<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst-pr" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Budget Pane</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para style="margin-bottom:10px; line-height:2.0;"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Budget Pane</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Budget</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> pane of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="MODFLOW_Output_Control_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">MODFLOW Output Control</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box is used to control how the budget terms are printed or saved. There are two types of budget data controlled here. There is an overall summary budget which is printed in the listing file and there are budget terms for individual cells. These may be either printed in the listing file or saved in an external binary file. If they are printed in the listing file, however, only some budget terms are printed. The budget terms for flow between cells, for example, are not printed in the listing file.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Compact budget</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> option is usually selected. It allows the budget terms for individual cells to be saved in a more compact format and also allows auxiliary data used by MODPATH to be saved. This option may be turned off if the budget file is to be used by an older program that does not know how to read the compact budget format.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-indent:0px; margin-right:0px; margin-left:0px; tabstops:none;"><snippet src="Frequency_and_N"/></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><anchor id="SaveCellFlows" styleclass="Normal"></anchor><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Save cell flows</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> option is used to control where the budget terms for individual cells are printed or saved. (The only place the summary budget can be printed is in the listing file.) The budget terms written to the listing file include the flows at boundary condition cells but not flows between active cells. The budget terms saved to binary file files include all flows including flows between active cells.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Save budget summary flow rates to a separate file (WBGT in MODFLOW-OWHM)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. MODFLOW-OWHM has an option to save the rate terms of the budget summary to a text file. If this option is activated, the flow rates will be saved to a file with the extension .&quot;wbgt.&quot;</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
