<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Changing the model to MODFLOW 6</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Changing the model to MODFLOW 6</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">As was mentioned, several time before, this model will not work with MODFLOW 6 without some changes. This is because of a change in the way the CHD package works in MODFLOW 6 as compared with MODFLOW-2005. In MODFLOW-2005, if two or more CHD boundaries were specified in the same cell, the final specified head for the cell would be the sum of the two specified heads. In MODFLOW 6, specifying more than one specified head in a single cell is an error. In this model, the object Interpolated_CHD_Boundary defines specified heads with two separate parameters. Each of those parameters defines a set of CHD boundaries in the cells intersected by the object. (See </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="CHD_Objects_with_Parameters" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">CHD Objects with Parameters</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.) To make the model work with MODFLOW 6, you must uncheck the checkbox for one of those parameters. After doing so, you can convert the model to MODFLOW 6 and it will run correctly. (You can convert the model to MODFLOW 6 by selecting </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Model Selection|MODFLOW 6</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. The conversion can happen before or after making the change to the CHD boundary.)</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="UncheckParameterBefore.png" scale="-99.90%" width="641" height="440" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Object Properties dialog box with checkboxes for both parameters still checked.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Object Properties dialog box with checkboxes for both parameters still checked.]]></caption></image><text styleclass="Image Caption" translate="true">   </text><image src="UncheckParameterAfter.png" scale="-99.90%" width="641" height="440" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Object Properties dialog box after the checkbox for the second parameter was unchecked.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Object Properties dialog box after the checkbox for the second parameter was unchecked.]]></caption></image></para>
  </body>
</topic>
