<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Custom Color Schemes Dialog Box</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Custom Color Schemes Dialog Box</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Custom Color Schemes</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box is used to define custom color schemes that can be used to determine how grid cells are colored or how contour lines are colored. To display the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Custom Color Schemes</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box, click the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Edit custom color schemes</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> button on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Color_Grid_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Color Grid</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> or </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Contour_Data_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Contour Data</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> pane of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Data_Visualization_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Data Visualization</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Each custom color scheme has a name and a series of fractions and their associated colors. When assigning a color to a grid cell or contour line, The color that is assigned will be picked by comparing the value assigned to the cell or contour line to the maximum and minimum values of all the cells or contour lines. For example, if the maximum value was 10 and the minimum value was zero, then the color assigned to a value of 4 would be the color associated with the fractional value of 0.4 [= (4-0)/(10-0)]. If you had assigned a color for a fraction of 0.4, that is the color that would be assigned. If you had not assigned a color to 0.4, then ModelMuse would interpolate between the fractions you did assign to determine the appropriate color to assign. The colors that are assigned are also affected by the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold; font-style:normal;" translate="true">Color adjustment factor</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and the number of </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Cycles</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The dialog box has several parts. On the left is a list of the custom color schemes that have already been defined. If none have already been defined, this list will be empty. Below the list of color schemes are buttons for adding, inserting, or deleting color schemes. You can hold your mouse over the buttons to see their names. If you want to define a new color scheme, click the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Add custom color scheme</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> button </text><image src="AddLayer.bmp" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption"></image><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. Once you have selected a custom color scheme from the list, you can edit it in the table to the right of the list. You will need to define a name for your color scheme and a series of fractions and their associated colors. The fractions should vary from 0 to 1. The colors are defined by hexadecimal values. The first two hexadecimal digits define how much blue is in the color. The middle two hexadecimal digits define how much green is in the color. The last two hexadecimal digits define how much red is in the color. If you click on a cell for the color, a button will appear. Click on that button to display a color dialog from which you can pick a color.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
