<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst-pr" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">GMG: Geometric Multigrid Package Pane</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para style="margin-bottom:10px; line-height:2.0;"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">GMG: Geometric Multigrid Package Pane</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The Geometric Multigrid (GMG) package is sometimes preferable to the PCG solver for large, steady state model because it can be faster and in some cases it can reach a satisfactory solution when other solvers do not. It requires more memory than the PCG package. The pane for this package is on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="MODFLOW_Packages_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">MODFLOW Packages and Programs</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box under </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Solver_Packages" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Solvers</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. The pane has two tabs: </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Control and Print</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Damping and Relax</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The following items are set on the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Control and Print</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab of the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">GMG: Geometric Multigrid Package</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> pane.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Residual convergence criterion (RCLOSE)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the residual convergence criterion for the inner iteration. The PCG algorithm computes the l2norm of the residual and compares it against RCLOSE. Typically, RCLOSE is set to the same value as HCLOSE (see below). If RCLOSE is set too high, then additional outer iterations may be required due to the linear equation not being solved with sufficient accuracy. On the other hand, a too restrictive setting for RCLOSE for nonlinear problems may force an unnecessarily accurate linear solution. This may be alleviated with the IITER parameter or with damping.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Maximum number of inner iterations (IITER)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the maximum number of PCG iterations for each linear solution. A value of 100 is typically sufficient. It is frequently useful to specify a smaller number for nonlinear problems so as to prevent an excessive number of inner iterations. </text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="LAK_Lake_Package_Pane" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Lake</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> package is used, </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="LAK" anchor="MoreIterations" domain="ModflowGuide.hmxp" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">more iterations</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> may be required.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Head change convergence criterion (HCLOSE)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the head change convergence criterion for nonlinear problems. After each linear solve (inner iteration), the maxnorm of the head change is compared against HCLOSE. HCLOSE can be set to a large number for linear problems; HCLOSE is ignored if MXITER=1.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Maximum number of outer iterations (MXITER)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the maximum number of outer iterations. For linear problems, MXITER can be set to 1. For nonlinear problems, MXITER needs to be larger, but rarely more than 100.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Multigrid preconditioner smoother (ISM)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is a flag that controls the type of smoother used in the multigrid preconditioner. The possible values for ISM and their meanings are as follows:</text></para>
    <list id="5" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="·" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If ISM = 0, then ILU(0) smoothing is implemented in the multigrid preconditioner. This smoothing requires an additional vector on each multigrid level to store the pivots in the ILU factorization. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If ISM = 1, then Symmetric GaussSeidel (SGS) smoothing is implemented in the multigrid preconditioner. No additional storage is required for this smoother; users may want to use this option if available memory is exceeded or nearly exceeded when using ISM=0. Using SGS smoothing is not as robust as ILU smoothing; additional iterations are likely to be required in reducing the residuals. In extreme cases, the solver may fail to converge as the residuals cannot be reduced sufficiently. </text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">GMG Output (IOUTGMG)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is a flag that controls the output of the GMG solver. The possible values of IOUTGMG and their meanings are as follows:</text></para>
    <list id="6" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="·" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If IOUTGMG = 0, then only the solver inputs are printed. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If IOUTGMG =1, then for each linear solve, the number of PCG iterations, the value of the damping parameter, the l2norm of the residual, and the maxnorm of the head change and its location (column, row, layer) are printed. At the end of a time/stress period, the total number of GMG calls, PCG iterations, and a running total of PCG iterations for all time/stress periods are printed. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If IOUTGMG = 2, then the convergence history of the PCG iteration is printed, showing the l2norm of the residual and the convergence factor for each iteration. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">IOUTGMG =3 is the same as IOUTGMG =1 except output is sent to the terminal instead of the MF2K LIST output file. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">IOUTGMG =4 is the same as IOUTGMG =2 except output is sent to the terminal instead of the MF2K LIST output file. </text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Print maximum head change values (IUNITMHC)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> controls output of maximum head change values:</text></para>
    <list id="7" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="·" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If IUNITMHC = 0, maximum head change values are not written to an output file. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If IUNITMHC &gt; 0, maximum head change values are written to an output file. </text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The following variables are on the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Damping and Relax</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab of the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">GMG: Geometric Multigrid Package</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> pane.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Damping parameter (DAMP)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the value of the damping parameter. For linear problems, a value of 1.0 should be used. For nonlinear problems, a value less than 1.0 but greater than 0.0 may be necessary to achieve convergence. A typical value for nonlinear problems is 0.5. Damping also helps control the convergence criterion of the linear solve to alleviate excessive PCG iterations.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Adaptive damping method (IADAMP)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is a flag that controls adaptive damping. The possible values of IADAMP and their meanings are as follows:</text></para>
    <list id="8" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="·" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If IADAMP = 0, then the value assigned to DAMP is used as a constant damping parameter. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If IADAMP = 1, the value of DAMP is used for the first nonlinear iteration. The damping parameter is adaptively varied on the basis of the head change, using Cooley’s method as described in Mehl and Hill (2001), for subsequent iterations. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If IADAMP = 2, the relative reduced residual damping method documented in Mehl and Hill (2001) and modified by Banta (2006) is used. </text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When IADAMP is specified as 2 and the value specified for DAMP is less than 0.5, the closure criterion for the inner iterations (DRCLOSE) is assigned simply as RCLOSE. When DAMP is between 0.5 and 1.0, inclusive, or when IADAMP is specified as 0 or 1, DRCLOSE is calculated according to equation 20 on p. 9 of Wilson and Naff (2004).</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Maximum damping value (DUP)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the maximum damping value that should be applied at any iteration when the solver is not oscillating; it is dimensionless. An appropriate value for DUP will be problem-dependent. For moderately nonlinear problems, reasonable values for DUP would be in the range 0.5 to 1.0. For a highly nonlinear problem, a reasonable value for DUP could be as small as 0.1. When the solver is oscillating, a damping value as large as 2.0*DUP may be applied.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Minimum damping value (DLOW)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the minimum damping value to be generated by the adaptive-damping procedure; it is dimensionless. An appropriate value for DLOW will be problem-dependent and will be smaller than the value specified for DUP. For a highly nonlinear problem, an appropriate value for DLOW might be as small as 0.001. Note that the value specified for the next variable, CHGLIMIT, could result in application of a damping value smaller than DLOW.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Maximum allowed head change (CHGLIMIT)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the maximum allowed head change at any cell between outer iterations; it has units of length. The effect of CHGLIMIT is to determine a damping value that, when applied to all elements of the head-change vector, will produce an absolute maximum head change equal to CHGLIMIT.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Semicoarsening control (ISC)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is a flag that controls semicoarsening in the multigrid preconditioner. The possible values of ISC and their meanings are given as follows:</text></para>
    <list id="9" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="·" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If ISC = 0, then the rows, columns and layers are all coarsened. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If ISC = 1, then the rows and columns are coarsened, but the layers are not. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If ISC = 2, then the columns and layers are coarsened, but the rows are not. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If ISC = 3, then the rows and layers are coarsened, but the columns are not. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If ISC = 4, then there is no coarsening. </text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Typically, the value of ISC should be 0 or 1. In the case that there are large vertical variations in the hydraulic conductivities, then a value of 1 should be used (see Remark 9 in “CoarseGrid Correction” section of Wilson and Naff (2004)). If no coarsening is implemented (ISC = 4), then the GMG solver is comparable to the PCG2 ILU(0) solver described in Hill (1990) and uses the least amount of memory.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Relaxation parameter (RELAX)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is a relaxation parameter for the ILU preconditioned conjugate gradient method. The RELAX parameter can be used to improve the spectral condition number of the ILU preconditioned system. The value of RELAX should be approximately one. However, the relaxation parameter can cause the factorization to break down. If this happens, then the GMG solver will report an assembly error and a value smaller than one for RELAX should be tried. This item is read only if ISC = 4.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
