<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst-pr" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">HFB: Horizontal Flow Barrier Package Pane</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para style="margin-bottom:10px; line-height:2.0;"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">HFB: Horizontal Flow Barrier Package Pane</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="HFB6" domain=".\ModflowGuide\ModflowGuide.hmxp" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Horizontal Flow Barrier (HFB)</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> package simulates thin, vertical low-permeability geologic features that impede the horizontal flow of groundwater. The pane for this package is on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="MODFLOW_Packages_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">MODFLOW Packages and Programs</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box under </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Flow_Packages" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Flow Packages</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. These geologic features are approximated as a series of horizontal-flow barriers conceptually situated on the boundaries between pairs of adjacent cells in the finite-difference grid. The key assumption underlying the HFB Package is that the width of the barrier is negligibly small in comparison with the horizontal dimensions of the cells in the grid. Barrier width is not explicitly considered in the Package, but is included implicitly in a hydraulic characteristic defined as either (1) barrier transmissivity divided by barrier width, if the barrier is in a constant-transmissivity layer, or (2) barrier hydraulic conductivity divided by barrier width, if the barrier is in a variable-transmissivity layer. Furthermore, the barrier is assumed to have zero storage capacity. Its sole function is to lower the horizontal branch conductance between the two cells that it separates. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In ModelMuse, the user specifies the hydraulic conductivity and thickness of the barrier. ModelMuse calculates the hydraulic characteristic of the barrier from these inputs. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Faults and slurry walls are both features that might be simulated with the Horizontal Flow Barrier package.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Parameters used in the Horizontal Flow Barrier package are defined in this pane. The only allowed parameter type is HFB, which defines values of the hydraulic characteristic of the barrier.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-indent:0px; margin-right:0px; margin-left:0px; tabstops:none;"><snippet src="Parameter_Names_and_Values"/></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="text-indent:0px; margin-right:0px; margin-left:0px; tabstops:none;"><snippet src="LinkToManageParameters"/></para>
  </body>
</topic>
