<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Import Points Dialog Box</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para style="margin-bottom:10px; line-height:2.0;"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Import Points Dialog Box</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">A common format for data are as a series of points with associated data. To import such data, the user selects </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">File|Import|Import Points...</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> to display the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Import Points</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. The dialog box has two tabs: </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Controls</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Data</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. Typically, the user sets the values on the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Controls</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab before switching to the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Data</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab to specify the data that will be imported. On the left side of the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Controls</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab is a list of data sets for which data can be imported. The data sets listed depend on where the data will be </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Evaluated at</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> (elements or nodes), their </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">View direction</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> (top, front, or side) and the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Number of (X, Y, or Z) formulas</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. These three choices are specified with radio buttons on the right side of the Controls tab. There are also options to specify the column and row instead of X and Y and to specify the layer instead of a Z formula. The user also specifies whether the imported objects </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Set values of intersected nodes or elements</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> or </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Set values of nodes or elements by interpolation</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. The names of the imported objects will be based on the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Root name</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> specified by the user. These options are explained in greater detail in the explanation of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Object_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Object Properties</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. The data will be imported either as a single object if the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Import as a single object with multiple sections</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> check box is checked, or as multiple objects. ModelMuse can usually handle a single object with multiple sections more efficiently than multiple objects.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The user can import data for the CHD, DRN, GHB, RIV, WEL, and HOB packages in MODFLOW with the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Import Points</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. The user can also import Footprint Wells in </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Footprint_Properties_Dialog_Bo" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Footprint</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> projects. However, importing data sets and features can not be done simultaneously. To import MODFLOW features, the user must first set the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Number of (X, Y, or Z) formulas</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> to One or Two and then select the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Feature</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> that is to be imported. If parameters have been defined for that feature, the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Parameter</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> can be set to one of them. The data related to the selected feature will appear on the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Data</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Once the user is satisfied with the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Controls</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab, the data to be imported are specified in the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Data</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab. The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Data</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab has a table in which the data to be specified are entered. The first two to four columns of the table are reserved for the coordinates of the data points. The remaining columns are used for the data to be imported. When importing data sets, the columns for the imported data can be rearranged by clicking down on a column header and dragging the column to a new position. The user can enter the required data into the table manually. When entering data manually, the user specifies the number of rows in the table in the edit box near the bottom of the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Data</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab. Another way to enter the data is to read them from a tab-delimited file or to paste them from the clipboard. In a tab-delimited file, each value is separated from the next value by a tab character. Each line in the file represents a separate data point. To read the data from a tab-delimited file, the user clicks the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Open file</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> button and selects the file from which the data are to be imported. When reading data from a file, blank lines and lines starting with &quot;#&quot; are skipped. To paste the data from the clipboard, put the data in a spreadsheet program, select the cells that hold the data, and copy them to the clipboard. Then the user goes back to the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Import Points</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box and selects the cell in the upper left corner of the space where the data belong. Pressing Ctrl-V on the keyboard will paste the data. If required, the number of rows in the table will be increased to accommodate the data that are pasted from the clipboard. Once the data have been entered into the table, the user presses the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">OK</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> button to import the data. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing boundary conditions or head observations, each row in the table on the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Data</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab that defines a new point will also define the start of a new object. Values for multiple times for a single object can be defined by leaving the cells in the table that define the location of a point empty. When importing head observations, the numbers used for the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">StatFlag</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> correspond to those used in the UCODE and the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Observation Name</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> will also be the name of the object.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">See also:</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Import_Gridded_Data_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Import Gridded/Mesh Data</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
