<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Import Distributed Data by Zone Dialog Box</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para style="margin-bottom:10px; line-height:2.0;"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Import Distributed Data by Zone Dialog Box</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PHAST has an option whereby a different value is specified for each node or element in a zone. The zone is defined by a pair of lower and higher coordinates in each of the three coordinate directions. The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Import Distributed Data by Zone</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box is used to import such data into ModelMuse. It is displayed by selecting </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">File|Import|Distributed Data by Zone..</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Importing data by zone is a good method for importing data when the data already exist in a zone format and when it is known that the grid will not be changed. If the grid will be changed or if the data are not already in a zone format, other methods such as importing point data are better because with the other methods, the data are specified in a grid-independent fashion. (See </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Import_Points_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Import Points</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box.)</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The user specifies the boundaries of the zones and the names of files containing the data to be imported. The user can either type in the path or use the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Browse</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> button to select the file. The dialog box can be resized if needed to display the full path name of a data file. When the user clicks the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">OK</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> button, the files will be read and the data will be imported. The format of the file is the same as that used by PHAST – a text file containing a list of data values. The values must be arranged so that all the values from lower layers precede values from high layers. Within the data for a layer, all values for lower rows precede values from higher rows. Within the data for a row, all values for lower columns precede values from higher columns. The data will be imported as a rectangular object with a formula for each data set for which the object sets the values. The formula will specify the value to apply to each node or element contained in the object. The coordinate system of the grid is used when specifying the coordinates. If the grid angle is not zero, the coordinate system of the grid is rotated relative to the global coordinate system. The user must select the view of the model to which the data will be imported (Top, Front, or Side). </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold; font-style:italic;" translate="true">The user must not change the grid or move the imported objects once the data have been imported</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> because the data read from the file must have the correct number of values for all the nodes or elements in the zone. If the grid is changed or the object is moved, the number of values may no longer be correct or the values may no longer be in the correct locations. If the grid must be changed, it is best to delete the imported objects and then import a new set of values that is correct for the modified grid.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
