<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2023-07-20T15:28:48.534-04:00" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Import Multiple Surfer Grid Files Dialog Box</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Import Multiple Surfer Grid Files Dialog Box</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Import Multiple Surfer Grid File</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box is used to import either binary or ASCII grid files generated by SURFER </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:Symbol;" translate="true">â</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> (</text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="http://www.goldensoftware.com/" target="_blank" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">http://www.goldensoftware.com/</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">). The data in each file is imported into ModelMuse as a single object on the top view of the model. Each data point in the grid file will be represented by a separate vertex in the imported objects. The dialog box is displayed by selecting </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">File|Import|Multiple Surfer Grid File...</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The imported data are used to set the values of new data sets. The user can determine whether the object that is imported will set the values of intersected cells or set values by interpolation. The user can choose an interpolation method for the new data set. (See </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Interpolation_Methods" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Interpolation Methods</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.) &#160;The name of the new data sets and the imported objects will be based on the name of the file from which the objects are imported. The </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Select_Objects_by_Name" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Select Objects by Name</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box can be used to select all this object at a later time. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The points from each file that is imported will set the values of a new data set. The points can set values of either the intersected cells or elements or be interpolated to all the cells or elements. The user can choose to import all the points in the file or to filter the points. If the points are more closely spaced than the grid spacing, filtering is recommended. When filtering the points, the user can choose to import the lowest value in a cell or element, the highest value in a cell or element, the mean average value in a cell or element, or the value of the point closest to the center of a cell or element.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
