<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Import MODFLOW-2005 or -NWT Model Dialog Box</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para style="margin-bottom:10px; line-height:2.0;"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Import MODFLOW-2005 or -NWT Model Dialog Box</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Import MODFLOW-2005 or -NWT Model</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box is used to import an existing MODFLOW-2005 or MODFLOW-NWT model into ModelMuse. It is displayed either by selecting </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">File|Import|Import MODFLOW-2005 or -NWT Model...</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Main_Window" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Main Window</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> or by selecting </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Import MODFLOW-2005 or MODFLOW-NWT model</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Start_Up_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Start-Up</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The dialog box has two tabs: </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Model</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Extract Submodel</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. The </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Model</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab is always used. The </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Extract Submodel</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab is used when the user wishes to create a new model that represents a portion of an existing model.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_"><text styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" translate="true">Model tab</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">X Origin</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Y Origin</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> represent the corner of the grid at row 1, column 1 (the upper, left corner). </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Grid angle</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> represents the angle in degrees that the grid is rotated counterclockwise. When extracting a submodel, the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">X Origin</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Y Origin</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> represent the coordinates of the corner of the full model - not the submodel. The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Name file</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the MODFLOW input file that lists the names of the other input and output files for MODFLOW. The MODFLOW name file is not required to have any particular extension, however, the extensions .nam, .mfn, and .modflow.in are sometimes used.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The imported model will have a series of objects that define the properties and boundary conditions of the model. All of these objects will be hidden initially. Once imported, the user can edit or execute the model in the normal way.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">For array data such as hydraulic conductivity or recharge rate, there are two different ways in which the data can be assigned. The best method depends on how the model will be used. If the grid might be changed, it is better to use interpolation to ensure that all cells are assigned appropriate values. If the grid will not be changed, assigning cells intersected by an object will allow the values to be assigned faster than assigning them by interpolation.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Although, ModelMuse can import MODFLOW models, it has some intrinsic limitations. Boundary conditions, such as wells, will be imported as points at the centers of cells. The exact coordinates of the wells are not preserved in the MODFLOW input files. Similarly, rivers are imported as a series of points rather than linear features because they are represented as a series of cells in MODFLOW rather than as line segments.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The following packages or input files are imported: Discretization input file, Basic package, Zone arrays input file, Multiplier arrays input file, BCF, CHD, CHOB, DE4, DRN, DROB, DRT, DE4, EVT, FHB, GAGE, GBOB, GHB, GMG, HFB, HOB, HYD, NWT, MNW1, MNW2, MNWI, PCG, PCGN, PVAL, RCH, RIV, RVOB, SFR, SIP, STOB, STR, SUB, SWI, SWR, SWT, UPW, and WEL.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The way that data are specified in MODFLOW can limit the ways in which an imported model is modified. For instance, most of the boundary condition packages such as the Well, River, Drain, and General-Head Boundary packages, define the locations of the boundary conditions using layer, row, and column numbers. If the grid is changed after importing a model, these boundary conditions may no longer be located appropriately. When importing boundary conditions defined by lists of cells such as the Well, River, Drain, and General-Head Boundary packages, separate objects are imported for each stress period. If some of these boundary conditions need to be deleted or have their values changed, it may prove easier to delete the objects that define the boundary conditions entirely and to redefine them based on the original data than to edit them. Adding additional boundary condition objects, on the other hand, can be done with little difficulty. Properties that are defined by arrays in MODFLOW, such as hydraulic conductivity, are less of a problem because a value will be assigned to every cell. However, in some cases, it may be desirable to change the interpolation method used in certain imported data sets. The Nearest Point interpolation method is typically used in imported data sets. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The program </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">MF2005_Importer.exe</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is used during the process of importing MODFLOW models. It is based on MODFLOW-2005. It reads data in the same way MODFLOW-2005 does and then writes that data in a simple format to the listing file for the model. ModelMuse then reads the data from the listing file. Thus, in the process of importing the model into ModelMuse, the existing listing file is replaced by one created by MF2005_Importer.exe. </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold; font-style:italic;" translate="true">If the user wishes to preserve the existing output files from the model, a copy of the model should be imported rather than the original version of the model.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Many MODFLOW-2000 models can be imported into ModelMuse in just the same way as the MODFLOW-2005 model. However, because of some differences in the input structure between MODFLOW-2000 and MODFLOW-2005, some MODFLOW-2000 models will have to be converted to MODFLOW-2005 models to be imported into ModelMuse. The program </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold; font-style:normal;" translate="true">MF2KtoMF05UC</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> can be used to convert MODFLOW-2000 to MODFLOW-2005 models. MF2KtoMF05UC can be obtained from </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="http://water.usgs.gov/nrp/gwsoftware/mf2ktomf05uc/mf2ktomf05uc.html" target="_blank" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">http://water.usgs.gov/nrp/gwsoftware/mf2ktomf05uc/mf2ktomf05uc.html</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">MODFLOW-96 models can not be imported into ModelMuse in the same way as MODFLOW-2005 models. However, the program </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">mf96to2k.exe,</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> which is distributed with MODFLOW-2000, can convert MODFLOW-96 models to MODFLOW-2000 models, which could then be imported as described above. MODFLOW-2000 can be obtained from </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="http://water.usgs.gov/nrp/gwsoftware/modflow2000/modflow2000.html" target="_blank" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">http://water.usgs.gov/nrp/gwsoftware/modflow2000/modflow2000.html</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. In many cases, it will be necessary to provide the elevations of the tops and bottoms of the layers in order to convert MODFLOW-96 models to MODFLOW-2000 models because those elevations are not necessarily included in the MODFLOW input.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If you wish to import just the MODFLOW grid, edit the name file so that all the files except the LIST, BAS and DIS file and any DATA or DATA(BINARY) files are commented out. You can also comment out any DATA or DATA(BINARY) files if they are used as output. Any line in the Name file that starts with &quot;#&quot; is considered a comment.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Some commercial versions of MODFLOW produce models that can not be read by the USGS version of MODFLOW. These will need to be modified to allow them to be run. Some common changes that might need to be made include the following.</text></para>
    <list id="4" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:&apos;Times New Roman&apos;; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Avoid using a unit numbers of 5 or 6.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">File names must not be surrounded by quotation marks.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">File names must not include spaces.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The USGS version of MODFLOW does not support the H5 format used by GMS.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Lines that refer to packages not included in the USGS version of MODFLOW-2005 or MODFLOW-NWT should be commented out. Some examples include:</text></li>
    </list>
    <list id="5" type="ol" listtype="lower-alpha" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#41;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:24px; font-family:&apos;Times New Roman&apos;; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">WHS</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">NDC</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ASP</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">CLB</text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_"><text styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" translate="true">Extract Submodel</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Extract Submodel</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab is used to create a new model representing a portion of an existing model. Such a model might be used in either of two ways.</text></para>
    <list id="6" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:&apos;Times New Roman&apos;; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">As a completely independent model. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">As a child model in MODFLOW-LGR (Local Grid Refinement). </text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When extracting a submodel, the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">X Origin</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Y Origin</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> represent the coordinates of the corner of the full model - not the submodel.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">There are two ways to specify the outline of the submodel area.</text></para>
    <list id="7" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="&#37;&#48;&#58;&#115;&#46;" format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:&apos;Times New Roman&apos;; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Using a polygon Shapefile that outlines the area to be included. (The Shapefile must be in the same projection used for the MODFLOW model.)</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Using starting and ending row and column numbers. If the submodel will be a MODFLOW-LGR child model, this method should be used.</text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">A polygon can be used to outline an irregular model outline. This is typically inappropriate for models intended to be child models in MODFLOW-LGR. If the model is intended to be a child model in MODFLOW-LGR, it is better to use starting and ending row and column numbers.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If the model is to be completely independent of the original model, specified head or specified flow boundaries along the edge of the submodel can be read from output files generated by the original model. However, this should not be done for models that will be used as child models with MODFLOW-LGR. In MODFLOW-LGR, the parent model supplies the boundary conditions along the edge of the child model grid automatically. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If the edge boundary conditions are to be read from the original model output files, either specified head or specified flow boundaries should be used but not both. If both are used, the specified head boundaries will override the specified flow boundaries. When a file is used to supply the edge boundary conditions, it is best for it to contain data for every time step.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The edge boundary conditions will be specified with the &quot;Flow and Head Boundary&quot; packages.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
