<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2024-06-14T14:30:14.632-04:00" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Import MODFLOW 6 Model Dialog Box</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Import MODFLOW 6 Model Dialog Box</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Import MODFLOW 6 Model</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box is used to import existing MODFLOW 6 models. The user specifies the simulation file for flow in the first edit box (labeled </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">MODFLOW 6 Simulation Name File for flow</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">). It can be accessed from the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Start_Up_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Start-Up</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box or by selecting </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">File|Import|MODFLOW 6 Model</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If a .usgs model reference file is available, its name can be specified in the edit box labeled </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">usgs.model.reference file (Optional)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. This file includes the coordinates of the upper left corner of the model and the model rotation among other things. This information can be used to geolocate models that use a structured grid if geolocation information is absent from the .dis file.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If there are separate simulations for solute transport, their simulation name files can be entered the table labeled &quot;MODFLOW 6 Simulation Name Files for transport (optional). If groundwater flow and transport are included in the same simulation, this table should be left empty.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_"><text styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" translate="true">Limitations</text></para>
    <list id="0" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The imported model may differ from the original model in some respects. It is advisable to compare the results of the imported and original model. If there are substantial differences, there may have been problem in importing the model.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse can not import model types other than flow models or solute transport models. Thus it can not import energy transport models or particle tracking models.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse can not import models that use DISU grids.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If a simulation includes more than one flow model, only one of the flow models can be imported.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse can not import exchanges among multiple flow models or among multiple solute transport models.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If the model contains more than one boundary package of the same type, all of the boundaries will be included in a single package. If the options of these packages are different, this may affect the model results.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing the lake package, it may happen that cells outside the model area will be identified as part of a lake if the lake is close to the edge of the model. If this occurs, the model can be fixed by selecting the erroneous vertices of the lake object and deleting them.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">All connections to any individual well in the Multiaquifer Well package must be vertically aligned.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The model input must be consistent with the MODFLOW input instructions.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse does not import flow-ja-face observations.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The order of boundary conditions in the imported model may be different from the original model. For example stream reaches may be numbered differently.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The imported model may specify more information in the Iterative Model Solution file than the original model.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse does not attempt to import the Output Control file.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The Ghost Node Correction package is only imported for DISV models. If this is a problem, specify the original GNC file in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="MODFLOW_Name_File_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Model|MODFLOW Name File</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The values imported for the Ghost Node Correction may differ from those in the original model. If this is a problem, replace the imported Ghost Node Correction file with the original file or specify the original GNC file in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="MODFLOW_Name_File_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Model|MODFLOW Name File</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In some cases, the encoding of a text input file may be a problem. In such cases, it may be possible to solve the problem by copying the contents of the file to another text file and then using the new file in the model in place of the old one.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing the Source and Sink Mixing package, boundary packages omitted from the Source and Sink Mixing package will still be included in the imported model. In addition, the Recharge and Evapotranspiration packages will always be specified as AUXMIXED in the imported model regardless of how they are specified in the imported model.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse may run out of memory when importing very large models.</text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
