<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Lake-Boundary Interaction Pane</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Lake-Boundary Interaction Pane</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Lake-Boundary Interaction</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> pane is on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="SUTRA_Options_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">SUTRA Options</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. It is used for setting parameters relating to the lake capability in SUTRA 3.0. Lakes can only be used in layered 3D models in which all of the nodes in all the layers are in the same horizontal position as in all other layers. The values assigned here can be overridden by values assigned to individual boundaries.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Default effect of lakes on sources or sinks of fluid &#160;(ILKF)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">: Effect that the presence or absence of lake water has on the application of fluid sources/sinks. When ILKF = -1, a fluid source/sink is applied to a node only when lake water is absent at that node. When ILKF=0, a fluid source/sink is a applied to a node whether lake water is present or absent at that node. When ILKF=1, a fluid source/sink is applied to a node only when lake water is present at that node.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Default effect of lakes on sources or sinks of solute mass or energy (ILKS)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">: Effect that the presence or absence of lake water has on the application of sources/sinks of solute mass or energy. When ILKS = -1, a source/sink of solute or energy is applied to a node only when lake water is absent at that node. When ILKS = 0, a source/sink of solute or energy is applied to a node whether lake water is present or absent at that node. When ILKS = 1, a source/sink of solute or energy is applied to a node only when lake water is present at that node.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Default effect of lakes on specified pressure boundaries (ILKP)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">: Effect that the presence or absence of lake water has on the application of specified pressures. When ILKP = -1, a specified pressure is applied to a node only when lake water is absent at that node. When ILKP = 0, a specified pressure is applied to a node whether lake water is present or absent at that node. When ILKP = 1, a specified pressure is applied to a node only when lake water is present at that node.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Default effect of lakes on specified concentration or temperature boundaries (ILKU)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">: Effect that the presence or absence of lake water has on the application of specified concentrations or temperatures. When ILKU = -1, a specified concentration or temperature is applied to a node only when lake water is absent at that node. When ILKU = 0, a specified concentration or temperature is applied to a node whether lake water is present or absent at that node. When ILKU = 1, a specified concentration or temperature is applied to a node only when lake water is present at that node.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Default effect of lakes on generalized-flow boundaries (ILKPG, CTIPG)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">: </text></para>
    <list id="2" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Strong" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ILKPG: Effect that the presence or absence of lake water has on the application of generalized-flow conditions. When ILKPG = -1, a generalized-flow condition is applied to a node only when lake water is absent at that node. When ILKPG = 0, a generalized-flow condition is applied to a node whether lake water is present or absent at that node. When ILKPG = 1, a generalized-flow condition is applied to a node only when lake water is present at that node.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">CTIPG: Type of interaction between the generalized-flow condition and lakes. </text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Strong" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">‘F’ = Interaction analogous to that between a fluid source/sink node and a lake</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">‘P’ = Interaction analogous to that between a specified-pressure node and a lake</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">(See section 3.2.3.3 of the SUTRA 3.0 documentation, “Interaction with Generalized-Flow Conditions.”)</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Default effect of lakes on generalized-transport boundaries (ILKUG. CTIUG)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">: </text></para>
    <list id="3" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Strong" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ILKUG: Effect that the presence or absence of lake water has on the application of generalized-transport conditions. When ILKUG = -1, a generalized-transport condition is applied to a node only when lake water is absent at that node. When ILKUG = 0, a generalized-transport condition is applied to a node whether lake water is present or absent at that node. When ILKUG = 1, a generalized-transport condition is applied to a node only when lake water is present at that node.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">CTIUG: Type of interaction between the generalized-flow condition and lakes. </text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Strong" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">‘S’ = Interaction analogous to that between a solute or energy source/sink node and a lake</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">‘U’ = Interaction analogous to that between a specified-concentration or specified-temperature node and a lake</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong" style="margin-left:24px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">(See section 3.2.3.7 of the SUTRA 3.0 documentation, “Interaction with Generalized-Transport Conditions.”)</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
