<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Main Menu and Buttons</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Main Menu and Buttons</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The options in the following sections are provided in the ModelMuse main menu. &#160;Each section starts with a table listing that briefly explains the menu items in the section. The buttons can be used to provide quick access to some of the menu items. In such cases, the picture on the button is shown next to the menu item both in the table and in the program. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">All of the menu items in ModelMuse have menu accelerators associated with them. Menu accelerators allow the user to navigate the menu without using the mouse. An underlined letter in the name of a menu item indicates the menu accelerator for that menu item. Some menu items also have shortcuts. A shortcut is indicated by a key sequence following the menu item. Shortcuts call a particular menu item directly without displaying the menu. For example, the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Edit|Undo</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> menu item has a menu accelerator of U (because the U in </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Undo</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is underlined) and a shortcut of Ctrl+Z (because “Ctrl+Z” follows </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Undo</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> in the menu). A menu item can be activated by holding down the Alt key and pressing the key on the keyboard corresponding to the menu accelerator. (On some systems, it may be necessary to hold down the Alt key to see the menu accelerators.) Menu items beneath the main menu can then be selected by typing the keys on the keyboard corresponding to their menu accelerators or using the arrow keys. For example, to use the menu accelerator for </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Edit|Undo</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">, the user would hold down the Alt key while pressing to E key to activate the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Edit</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> main menu item and then would press the U key to activate </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Undo</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. To use the shortcut for </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Edit|Undo</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">, the user would hold down the Ctrl key while pressing the Z key. This would call the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Undo</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> menu item but unlike an accelerator, the menu would never be displayed.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">For menu items or accelerators to work, the ModelMuse window must have the input focus. Clicking on a window with the mouse will generally give that window the focus.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
