<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">MODFLOW 6 Example: Define Recharge</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">MODFLOW 6 Example: Define Recharge</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Next we will define recharge in the model. However, we will exclude the polygon for the farm that defines the unsaturated zone flow because we assume that any recharge is already included in the Infiltration defined for the UZF package.</text></para>
    <list id="7" type="ol" listtype="decimal" formatstring="%0:s." format-charset="DEFAULT_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:'Times New Roman'; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Click on the "Create rectangle object" button </text><image src="CreateRectangle.png" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption"></image><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. We will create a rectangle that completely surrounds the grid. Click outside the grid near one of the corners of the grid. Then click again outside the grid at the diagonally opposite corner of the grid. When the Object Properties dialog box appears. just click OK to close the dialog box without doing anything else. </text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Click on the "Add polygon sections" button </text><image src="AddPolygons.bmp" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption"></image><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. Hold the Shift key on the keyboard down and move close to one of the vertices of the polygon that defines the farm. When you get close enough a black dot will appear near the end of the pointer arrow for the cursor. If you click when the pointer is in this state, the vertex that is created will line up exactly with the nearby vertex of the other object. Trace the outline of the farm object while holding the shift key down and clicking at each corner of the farm object. Double-click to finish adding a polygon section. The new section of the object defines a hole in the object.</text><br /><image src="Modflow6ExampleRchLocation.bmp" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Recharge location</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Recharge location]]></caption></image></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Click the "Select objects" button </text><image src="Select.png" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption"></image><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and double-click on the object to display the Object Properties dialog box.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In the Object Properties dialog box, make sure the the formulas for the higher and lower Z coordinates are "Model_Top" and "Upper_Aquifer_Bottom" respectively so that the object applies to cells in the top layer.</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Switch to the MODFLOW Features tab and check the checkbox for the Recharge package. Set the starting and ending times to -1 and 0. Set the recharge rate to 1E-10.</text><br /><image src="Modflow6ExampleRchRate.bmp" scale="-99.90%" width="472" height="352" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Recharge rate</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Recharge rate]]></caption></image></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Click OK to close the dialog box.</text></li>
    </list>
  </body>
</topic>
