<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2023-03-06T08:19:07.782-05:00" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">NPF: Node Property Flow Package Pane</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">NPF: Node Property Flow Package Pane</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The Node Property Flow package is the package used to calculate flow between cells in MODFLOW 6. The </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">NPF: Node Property Flow Package</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> pane is on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="MODFLOW_Packages_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">MODFLOW Packages and Programs</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box under </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Flow_Packages" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Flow Packages</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When the Well package in MODFLOW-NWT is used, a warning similar to the following will always be printed to the listing file.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="" style="text-align:left; text-indent:0px; margin-top:0px; margin-right:0px; margin-bottom:0px; margin-left:0px; line-height:1.00; background-color:transparent; white-space:normal; page-break-inside:auto; page-break-after:auto; border:none; tabstops:none;"><text style="font-family:&apos;Courier New&apos;; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;" translate="true"> NEGATIVE PUMPING RATES WILL BE REDUCED IF HEAD </text></para>
    <para styleclass="" style="text-align:left; text-indent:0px; margin-top:0px; margin-right:0px; margin-bottom:0px; margin-left:0px; line-height:1.00; background-color:transparent; white-space:normal; page-break-inside:auto; page-break-after:auto; border:none; tabstops:none;"><text style="font-family:&apos;Courier New&apos;; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;" translate="true"> FALLS WITHIN THE INTERVAL PHIRAMP TIMES THE CELL </text></para>
    <para styleclass="" style="text-align:left; text-indent:0px; margin-top:0px; margin-right:0px; margin-bottom:0px; margin-left:0px; line-height:1.00; background-color:transparent; white-space:normal; page-break-inside:auto; page-break-after:auto; border:none; tabstops:none;"><text style="font-family:&apos;Courier New&apos;; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;" translate="true"> THICKNESS. THE VALUE SPECIFIED FOR PHIRAMP IS &#160;0.10000E+00</text></para>
    <para styleclass="" style="text-align:left; text-indent:0px; margin-top:0px; margin-right:0px; margin-bottom:0px; margin-left:0px; line-height:1.00; background-color:transparent; white-space:normal; page-break-inside:auto; page-break-after:auto; border:none; tabstops:none;"><text style="font-family:&apos;Courier New&apos;; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;" translate="true"> WELLS WITH REDUCED PUMPING WILL BE REPORTED TO FILE UNIT NUMBER &#160;141</text></para>
    <para styleclass="" style="text-align:left; text-indent:0px; margin-top:0px; margin-right:0px; margin-bottom:0px; margin-left:0px; line-height:1.00; background-color:transparent; white-space:normal; page-break-inside:auto; page-break-after:auto; border:none; tabstops:none;"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In the Node Property Flow package, there are four methods of calculating the transmissivity between blocks in the horizontal direction. These are:</text></para>
    <list id="0" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">(default)—Harmonic mean (This is most appropriate for confined and unconfined aquifers with abrupt boundaries in transmissivity at the cell boundaries or for confined aquifers with uniform hydraulic conductivity.)</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">LOGARITHMIC—Logarithmic mean (This is most appropriate for confined aquifers with gradually varying transmissivities.)</text></li>
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">AMT-LMK—Arithmetic mean of saturated thickness and logarithmic-mean hydraulic conductivity. (This is most appropriate for unconfined aquifers with gradually varying transmissivities.)</text></li>
    </list>
    <list id="1" type="ul" listtype="bullet" formatstring="&#183;" format-charset="SYMBOL_CHARSET" levelreset="true" legalstyle="false" startfrom="1" styleclass="Normal" style="font-family:Symbol; font-size:12pt; color:#000000;">
      <li styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">AMT-HMK—Arithmetic mean of saturated thickness and harmonic-mean hydraulic conductivity. </text></li>
    </list>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The Node Property Flow package also has a number of options. The user can select an option by checking the appropriate checkboxes. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><anchor id="K22OVERK" styleclass="Strong"></anchor><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Use horizontal anisotropy (K22OVERK)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> indicates that horizontal anisotropy will be defined in the data set Ky_Over_Kx. That data set will be exported as the K22 data set in MODFLOW 6. MODFLOW 6 will multiply the values in the input file by the corresponding value of K to determine the final Ky values.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Use vertical anisotropy (K33OVERK)</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> indicates that vertical anisotropy will be defined in the data set Kz_Over_Kx That data set will be exported as the K33 data set in MODFLOW 6. MODFLOW 6 will multiply the values in the input file by the corresponding value of K to determine the final Kz values.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><anchor id="XT3D" styleclass="Strong"></anchor><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">XT3D</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> indicates that the XT3D formulation will be used. If the RHS keyword is also included, then the XT3D additional terms will be added to the right-hand side. If the RHS keyword is excluded, then the XT3D terms will be put into the coefficient matrix. Use of XT3D will substantially increase the computational effort, but will result in improved accuracy for anisotropic conductivity fields and for unstructured grids in which the Control Volume Finite Difference (CVFD) requirement is violated. The XT3D option can not be used with the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="GNC_Ghost_Node_Correction_Pack" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Ghost-Node Correction</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> package.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Numerical models, such as the GWF Model, formulate a nonlinear system of equations of the form </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Ax “ b, </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">where A is the coefficient matrix, x is the vector of dependent variables (for example, head, stage, and concentration), and b is the right-hand-side vector. If the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">RHS</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> keyword is also included, then the XT3D additional terms will be added to the righthand side. If the RHS keyword is excluded, then the XT3D terms will be put into the coefficient matrix. This has the effect of causing certain values in the equation to be evaluated using values from the previous iteration or time step rather than from the current iteration of the time step. When the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">RHS</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> option is used, the simulation will require less memory and computational effort &#160;per iteration than if it is not used but may require more iterations.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">THICKSTRT</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> option indicates that cells having a negative ICELLTYPE are confined, and their cell thickness for conductance calculations will be computed as the initial head minus the cell bottom &#160;rather than the cell top minus the cell bottom.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">VARIABLECV</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> indicates that the vertical conductance will be calculated using the saturated thickness and properties of the overlying cell and the thickness and properties of the underlying cell. If the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">DEWATERED</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> keyword is also specified, then the vertical conductance is calculated using only the saturated thickness and properties of the overlying cell if the head in the underlying cell is below its top. If these keywords are not specified, then the default condition is to calculate the vertical conductance at the start of the simulation using the initial head and the cell properties. The vertical conductance remains constant for the entire simulation.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">DEWATERED</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> keyword is specified, then the vertical conductance is calculated using only the saturated thickness and properties of the overlying cell if the head in the underlying cell is below its top.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">PERCHED</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> indicates that when a cell is overlying a dewatered convertible cell, the head difference used in Darcy’s Law is equal to the head in the overlying cell minus the bottom elevation of the overlying cell. If not specified, then the default is to use the head difference between the two cells.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">SAVE_SPECIFIC_DISCHARGE</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> indicates that x, y, and z components of specific discharge will be calculated at cell centers and written to the cell-by-cell flow file, which is specified with “BUDGET SAVE FILE” in Output Control. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">SAVE_SATURATION</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> indicates that cell saturation will be written to the budget file, which is specified with “BUDGET SAVE FILE” in Output Control. Saturation will be saved to the budget file as an auxiliary variable saved with the DATA-SAT text label. Saturation is a cell variable that ranges from zero to one and can be used by post processing programs to determine how much of a cell volume is saturated. If ICELLTYPE is 0, then saturation is always one.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Some of the NPF options can not be used together or with the Newton formulation specified on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Wetting_Tab" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Wetting Tab</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="MODFLOW_Options_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">MODFLOW Options dialog box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. ModelMuse prevents the user from selecting incompatible options by disabling some options that are incompatible with the selected options.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
