<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">PEST Properties Pilot Points Pane</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">PEST Properties Pilot Points Pane</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The Pilot Points tab is on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST Properties Dialog Box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">This pane is used to define the locations of pilot points and to specify whether or not pilot point locations will be displayed.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Pilot points are explained in the manuals for PLPROC and the PEST Groundwater Utilities. PLPROC and the PEST Groundwater Utilities are available from the PEST home page (</text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="https://pesthomepage.org/" target="_blank" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">https://pesthomepage.org/</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">). ModelMuse uses PLPROC to implement pilot points. Section 4 of the documentation for the PEST Groundwater Utilities provides a conceptual description of pilot points and how they are used. In brief, pilot points provide a way for the parameter estimation process in PEST determine a suitable spatial distribution of model input values without the user being required to specify a zonation of the parameter values. For instance, suppose we wanted to estimate the hydraulic conductivity of an aquifer. From aquifer tests, we may know that the hydraulic conductivity varies from place to place but we might not have a clear idea of how it varies spatially. One way to approach this would be to specify zones within the aquifer and to have PEST estimate separate uniform parameter values within each zone. The problem with this approach is that we don&apos;t know where the boundaries of the zones should be. Pilot points provide a way to get around this problem. The modeler would designate a number of points and assign a value to each point. Between points, values would be assigned to each cell via kriging. Within PEST, the value assigned to each pilot point would be a parameter that can be adjusted by PEST to improve the fit between the observed and simulated values. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Pilot points are typically used with regularization where constraints are applied to the pilot point values so that pilot points that are close to one another will be assigned similar values.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Pilot points can be combined with zones if desired. In such cases, a set of pilot points will be selected from all the pilot points that have been defined. A pilot point will be included in the set used for a particular zone if it falls within the zone or if it no further away then the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Pilot point buffer</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> from a cell center (MODFLOW) or node or element center (SUTRA) from that is part of the zone.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The locations of pilot points can be defined in several ways. If desired, the various methods can be combined. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">A common method is to have a series of </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Regularly spaced pilot points</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> in which the pilot points form either squares or equilateral triangles. For this method, the user selects the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Pattern</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Pilot point spacing</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The user can also specify the locations of individual pilot points individually. This is often used to supplement the pilot points specified in a regular pattern when there is reason to &#160;believe that more detail is required in a specific retgion. The table within the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Individually specified pilot points</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> panel displays the location of these points. The data can be typed into the table or imported from Shapefiles or text files. With text files, each line must contain the X and Y coordinates of a point and the coordinates must be separated by a comma, space, or tab character. If the data are in a spreadsheet, the data can be copied from the spreadsheet to the clipboard and then pasted into the table by selecting a cell of the table and pressing the keyboard combination Ctrl-V. Finally, if </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Show candidate pilot points</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is checked, the user can close the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST Properties Dialog Box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and select </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Edit|Add Pilot Point</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. then when the user clicks on the top view of the model with the mouse, a new pilot point will be created at the location of the mouse click. This command can also be accessed by clicking the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Add pilot point</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">&#32;</text><image src="AddPilotPoint.png" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Screen capture of the Add pilot point button.</title></image><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> button.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Yet another way to define pilot points is to have ModelMuse create them </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Between point observations</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
