<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2024-07-29T20:56:20.273-04:00" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">PestObsGroupProperties</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">PestObsGroupProperties</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">OBGNME</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is the name of the observation group. Observation group names can be up to 12 characters in length. However, if an observation group is used for regularization, its name must be start with the prefix &quot;regul_&quot; which means that the rest of the group name can only be 6 characters in length. The prefix will be automatically added if the check box in the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Regularization Group</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> column is checked. Prior information groups typically are regularization groups but regular observation groups typically are not regularization groups.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">GTARG</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is an optional group-specific target measurement objective function. To include it, check the check box in the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Use Group Target</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> column and specify the value in the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Group Target</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> column.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">COVFLE</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> If a covariance matrix is used for observation weights assignment for a particular observation group, COVFLE is the name of the file holding the covariance matrix for that group. The roles of observation and prior information covariance matrices are discussed in section 3.7 of the PEST User Manual and in Doherty (2015). The formatting of observation covariance matrix files is discussed in section 4.19 of the PEST User Manual.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
