<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">PEST Examples</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">PEST Examples</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The examples presented here are all variations of the Rocky Mountain Arsenal example. A previous tutorial shows how to simulate this conceptual model with </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Rocky_Mountain_Arsenal" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">MODFLOW-2005</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. Here, we will start with working MODFLOW 6, MODFLOW-2005, and SUTRA models and show how to use PEST with each of them. Subfolders of the PEST example folder each contain three ModelMuse files. One of the files is used as the starting point of the exercise. Another model is a modified version of the first with spatially varying hydraulic conductivity and a different infiltration rate in a discharge pond. This was treated as the true model and was used to generate simulated values to use in the exercise. The final file contains the completed model after it has been set up to perform parameter estimation.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The goal of these exercises is to learn how to specify observations and use parameters for both data sets and boundary conditions in ModelMuse and to learn how to visualize the characteristics of the calibrated model.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Before diving into how to use PEST with these example, let&apos;s review the conceptual model. The aquifer is simulated as confined. The steady-state model has a lake at the northern end and a stream at the southern end both of which are modeled as specified head boundaries. The lake has a head of 75 m. The stream head varies from 23.5 m near its eastern end to 5 m near its western end. Bedrock outcrops on the east, west, and south sides define the edges of the model. In addition, two bedrock outcrops within the model area are treated as inactive areas. A disposal pond in the northern half of the study area acts as a source of water and solute in addition to the lake. There are two production wells in the southern half of the model. The disposal pond is a potential source of contaminants to the production wells. The model is intended to help assess this problem. In the uncalibrated version of the model the flow rate out of the disposal pond is estimated at 0.03 m</text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-size:8pt; vertical-align:super;" translate="true">3</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">/s. The estimated hydraulic conductivity is 0.0001 m/s. The models all have head observations and a flow observation. The head observations are scattered throughout the model area. the flow observation encompasses part of the discharge into the stream. The parameters to be estimated are the hydraulic conductivity and the flow rate of the disposal pond.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Because this model has only confined layers and the only boundary conditions are specified heads and specified flows, it is a linear model. That should make estimating parameters for this model easier than would often be the case.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Image"><image src="rmamap.emf" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image"><title translate="true">Diagram of Rocky Mountain Arsenal model area.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Diagram of Rocky Mountain Arsenal model area.]]></caption></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
