<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" modified="2022-01-20T10:50:43.371-05:00" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Pilot Point Explanation</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Pilot Point Explanation</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Manage_Parameters_Dialog_Box" anchor="PilotPoints" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">A PEST parameter can be associated with pilot points</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> (Doherty, 2003; Doherty and others, 2010). Pilot point approaches used in ModelMuse5 are explained in the manuals for PLPROC and the PEST Groundwater Utilities available from the PEST home page (</text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="&lt;%LINK_CAPTION%&gt;" target="_blank" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">https://pesthomepage.org/</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">). ModelMuse uses PLPROC to implement pilot points. Section 4 of the documentation for the PEST Groundwater Utilities provides a conceptual description of pilot points and how they are used. In brief, pilot points are a parameterization device that facilitates increased parameter flexibility by estimating properties at user-specified locations in the grid; the remainder of the grid is then filled by kriging. &#160;Pilot points can be grouped with zonation, but such zonation is not required. For instance, suppose the hydraulic conductivity of an aquifer is being estimated. From aquifer tests, it may be known that the hydraulic conductivity varies from place to place but the spatial variation might not be well defined. One way to approach this would be to specify zones within the aquifer and to have PEST estimate separate uniform parameter values within each zone. A potential drawback of this approach is that the chosen zonation might not be optimal. Pilot points provide a way to get around this problem. The modeler designates a number of points and assigns a value to each point. Between points, values are assigned to each cell via kriging. Within PEST, the value assigned to each pilot point is a parameter that can be adjusted by PEST to improve the fit between the observed and simulated values. If all pilot points are tied in the PEST control file, they will act like a zone. Likewise, a zone with zero or on associated pilot points will also produce zone-like results. Such aspects can be useful in stepwise modeling, where model complexity is added in sequential steps in response to model performance. </text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
