<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Pilot Point Explanation</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Pilot Point Explanation</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Manage_Parameters_Dialog_Box" anchor="PilotPoints" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">A PEST parameter can be associated with pilot points</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. Pilot points are explained in the manuals for PLPROC and the PEST Groundwater Utilities. PLPROC and the PEST Groundwater Utilities are available from the PEST home page (</text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="https://pesthomepage.org/" target="_blank" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">https://pesthomepage.org/</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">). ModelMuse uses PLPROC to implement pilot points. Section 4 of the documentation for the PEST Groundwater Utilities provides a conceptual description of pilot points and how they are used. In brief, pilot points provide a way for the parameter estimation process in PEST to determine a suitable spatial distribution of model input values without the user being required to specify a zonation of the parameter values. For instance, suppose we wanted to estimate the hydraulic conductivity of an aquifer. From aquifer tests, we may know that the hydraulic conductivity varies from place to place but we might not have a clear idea of how it varies spatially. One way to approach this would be to specify zones within the aquifer and to have PEST estimate separate uniform parameter values within each zone. The problem with this approach is that we don&apos;t know where the boundaries of the zones should be. Pilot points provide a way to get around this problem. The modeler would designate a number of points and assign a value to each point. Between points, values would be assigned to each cell via kriging. Within PEST, the value assigned to each pilot point would be a parameter that can be adjusted by PEST to improve the fit between the observed and simulated values. </text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
