<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">RmaMF6: Run PEST</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">RmaMF6: Run PEST</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">After making all the changes to the model, you have to run the model from ModelMuse one more time. Select </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">File|Export|MODFLOW 6 Input Files</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. ModelMuse will start a command line window that will in turn start ModelMonitor to run the model. When the model is done running close ModelMonitor. Several more operations will be performed in the command line window and then the MODFLOW listing file will be opened in a text editor. Let&apos;s take a look at those other operations that are performed between ModelMonitor closing and the MODFLOW listing file being opened.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The first thing that happens after ModelMonitor is closed is that </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Mf6ObsExtractor" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Mf6ObsExtractor</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> is run. It creates an instruction file that will be used by PEST when it is running. The second thing that happens is that PLPROC is run. It is a utility program that can be downloaded from the PEST homepage. It creates a file that will be used when interpolating among the pilot points.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="RmaMF6CommandLineAll.png" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Annotated screen capture identifying purposes of commands in the RunModflow.bat batchfile.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Annotated screen capture identifying purposes of commands in the RunModflow.bat batchfile.]]></caption></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In addition to creating the input files for MODFLOW, ModelMuse also created the PEST control file when it ran MODFLOW along with two batch files named RunPestChek.bat and RunPest.bat. PESTCHEK is a PEST utility program that checks the PEST input for errors. It is a good idea to always run PESTCHEK before attempting to run PEST. You can run PESTCHEK by double clicking on the RunPestChek.bat file in Windows Explorer. If it reports errors, you will need to fix them. If something is wrong with your parameters, observations, pilot points, or delimiters, you may need to run the model again after fixing them. Otherwise, you will probably just need to export the PEST control file again after fixing the problem in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST Properties</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. To export the PEST control file again, select </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">File|Export|PEST|Export PEST Control File</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. The Save File dialog box will have options to run PESTCHEK, PEST, or not run anything. Choose the option you prefer. When PESTCHECK doesn&apos;t report any errors, you are ready to run PEST. Go ahead and run PEST. You should expect PEST to take more than an hour to finish.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When PEST has finished running, you may wish to back up your model input and output files, so you don&apos;t accidentally overwrite them later on if you run ModelMuse again.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
