<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2022-04-28T11:39:15.467-04:00" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">RmaSutra: Define Parameters and Parameter Groups</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">RmaSutra: Define Parameters and Parameter Groups</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The next step is to define parameters. Select </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Model|Manage Parameters... </text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In the Manage Parameters dialog box, Set the number of parameters to 2. We will define two parameters: K and Seepage. During parameter estimation, the data already specified in the model will be multiplied by the parameter value. Initially we will assign both parameters a value of 1 so that the multiplication will leave the model data unchanged. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">K will affect the maximum and minimum hydraulic conductivities and Seepage will affect the flow rate from the seepage pond. In SUTRA models, PEST parameters are the only allowed parameter type. We will assign a value of 1 to both parameters. We want to estimate the distribution of hydraulic conductivity, not just its average value. Pilot points can be used to do that, so we will use pilot points with the K parameter. Parameters that cannot go negative are typically log transformed (Doherty and Hunt, 2010) so we will also log transform the K parameter, but we will not use any transformation for the Seepage parameter as the pond can be gaining (negative sign) or losing (positive sign) to the groundwater system. We will use “factor” for the change limitation for both K and Seepage. The lower and upper bounds for the K parameter are 0.01 and 100 respectively. The lower and upper bounds for the Seepage parameter are 0.001 and 100 respectively. The scale and offset are set to 1 and 0 respectively for both parameters. On the Parameter Groups tab, set the number of parameter groups to 2. Name the parameter groups “KGrp” and “WellGr” as shown in the second illustration below. We will use all the default values for the parameter groups.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="RmaMf6_ManageParameters.png" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption" figurelistinclude="0"><title translate="true">Screen capture of the Manage Parameters dialog box showing properties assigned to K and Seepage parameters.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Screen capture of the Manage Parameters dialog box showing properties assigned to K and Seepage parameters.]]></caption></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="RmaMf6_ManageParameters2.png" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption" figurelistinclude="0"><title translate="true">Screen capture of the Manage Parameters dialog box showing properties assigned to KGrp and WellGr parameter groups.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Screen capture of the Manage Parameters dialog box showing properties assigned to KGrp and WellGr parameter groups.]]></caption></image></para>
  </body>
</topic>
