<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Running PEST</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Running PEST</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Before running PEST, you must first activate PEST and run the model from ModelMuse. The batch file to run the model will contain a command to create an instruction file for PEST. There will be a related command in the RunModel.bat batch file that will extract the simulated values corresponding to the observations in the format described by the instruction file.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Once the model is running properly without using PEST and all the parameters and observations have been defined, you should run the model again from ModelMuse. The command that ModelMuse will run does more than just run the model. If there are pilot points used, the command will create a file used in interpolating among the pilot points. It also creates an instruction file for PEST to use when attempting to extract simulated values from the model results. Next, you can run PEST by selecting </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">File|Export|PEST|Export PEST Control File</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. There will be three radio buttons at the bottom of the Save As dialog box. They will be labeled </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Don&apos;t run</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">, </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run PESTCHEK</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">, and </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run PEST</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. By default, </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run PESTCHEK</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> will be selected. It is always a good idea to run PESTCHEK before attempting to run PEST. If PESTCHEK detects any errors, you must correct them before attempting to run PEST. If the errors involve parameters or observations, you may need to rerun the model. Otherwise, you may be able to make corrections in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST Properties</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box and export the PEST control file again without exporting all the model input files.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Once no errors are detected by PESTCHEK, you can run PEST by selecting </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run PEST</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> in the Save As dialog box.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
