<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Running PEST</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Running PEST</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When exporting the model input files, ModelMuse creates two separate batch files to run the model. One of them is named RunModel.bat and will be used by PEST to run the model. The other will be named RunModflow.bat or RunSutra.bat. The latter batch files must be run once before starting PEST. The RunModflow.bat or RunSutra.bat will contain an run a utility program to create an instruction file for PEST. They may also have instructions to run PLPROC scripts that will calculate kriging factors. The RunModel.bat file will contain an run a utility program to extract simulated values in the format specified in the instruction file. The RunModel.bat may also perform kriging interpolation among pilot points using the kriging factors generated with the RunModflow.bat or RunSutra.bat files.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Once the model is running properly without using PEST and all the parameters and observations have been defined, you should run the model once from ModelMuse. This ensures that the instruction file for PEST and any required kriging factors files will be created. Next, you can run PEST by selecting </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">File|Export|PEST|Export PEST Control File</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. There will be three radio buttons at the bottom of the Save As dialog box. They will be labeled </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Don&apos;t run</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">, </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run PESTCHEK</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">, and </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run PEST</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. By default, </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run PESTCHEK</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> will be selected. It is always a good idea to run PESTCHEK before attempting to run PEST. If PESTCHEK detects any errors, you must correct them before attempting to run PEST. If the errors involve parameters or observations, you may need to rerun the model. Otherwise, you may be able to make corrections in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST Properties</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box and export the PEST control file again without exporting all the model input files.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Once no errors are detected by PESTCHEK, you can run PEST by selecting </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run PEST</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> in the Save As dialog box. It is also possible to run PESTCHEK or PEST using batch files named RunPestChek.bat and RunPest.bat. They are created at the same time the model input files are created.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
