<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">SUPCALC Options Dialog Box</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">SUPCALC Options Dialog Box</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The SupCalc Options dialog box is used to run the SUPCALC PEST Utility program documented in the PEST User Manual Part II Section 8.6 to calculate the number of superparameters that can be used with SVD-Assist (Singular Value Decomposition Assist). If the user clicks OK, a batch file named RunSupCalc.bat will be created that will start SUPCALC. It is displayed by selecting </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">File|Export|PEST|Calculate Number of Super-Parameters</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. &#160;</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">PEST control file name</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> This is the name of the PEST control file to be used by SUPCALC. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">For computation of super parameters use:</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> X is the Jacobian matrix J. The outcome of SUPCALC’s deliberations should not depend on your choice; however SUPCALC execution time may depend on which of these options you select. If in doubt, choose the first option as it is often much quicker.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Expected value of measurement objective function</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> If you have not as yet calibrated the model this will be a difficult question to answer. If you supply an answer which is too low, SUPCALC will probably inform you that the dimensions of the calibration solution space are greater than is actually sustainable by the data. If your answer is too high then SUPCALC may underestimate the dimensions of the calibration solution space. However, given the approximate nature of SUPCALC’s calculations, and the fact that in most modelling contexts the level of fit is determined more by so-called “structural noise” than by measurement noise, these considerations are probably of secondary importance. Furthermore, in many real-world modelling contexts the boundary between the solution and null spaces is “soft” because the minimum of the parameter projection error variance curve that SUPCALC seeks to find is difficult to establish; this is because the number of singular values over which near-minimal values are calculated is often quite broad.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run PEST before SupCalc to generate .jco file</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> If PEST is run before SUPCALC, ModelMuse first backs up the PEST control file. and then writes a new one. When SUPCALC finishes running, the backed up PEST control file is restored.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Run SupCalc</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> If this is checked, the RunSupCalc.bat file generated by ModelMuse will be started to run SUPCALC.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The name of the output file of SUPCALC will terminate with &quot;_SupCalcOut.txt.&quot;</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Strong"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">See also: </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Using_Singlular_Value_Decompos" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Using SVD Assist</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
