<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Unsupported PEST Capabilities</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Unsupported PEST Capabilities</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The Sensitivity Reuse section of the PEST control file is not supported by ModelMuse. In chapter 7 of the PEST manual where the Sensitivity Reuse section is explained it says “Keep in mind also, that PEST’s SVD-assist functionality achieves a similar outcome, but in a more sophisticated fashion. Hence activation of PEST’s sensitivity reuse functionality is not, in general, advisory.” ModelMuse does support PEST’s SVD-assist functionality.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Automatic User Intervention is not supported by ModelMuse. In chapter 6.3 of the PEST documentation, it states “Before describing PEST’s automatic user intervention functionality in detail, it should be pointed out that truncated singular value decomposition as a solution process for an ill-posed inverse problem plays a similar role to that of automatic user intervention; however it is far more effective and far more efficient than automatic user intervention in stabilizing the solution process of that problem.” ModelMuse does support PEST’s truncated singular value decomposition.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The Derivatives Command Line Section is not supported by ModelMuse because the models supported by ModelMuse do not have the capability of writing any elements of the Jacobian matrix.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
