<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Using Parameters with Data Sets</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Using Parameters with Data Sets</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">For MODFLOW-2005 and related models, parameters can be defined for some packages using capabilities built directly into MODFLOW. Built-in parameters have been eliminated from MODFLOW 6 but ModelMuse still allows you to use MODFLOW-2005 style parameters for some packages by generating MODFLOW 6 input files based on how parameters were used with MODFLOW-2005. For SUTRA, MODFLOW 6, MODFLOW-2005 and related models, the user can also define parameters that are unrelated to any package. Their parameter type is identified as "PEST" in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Manage_Parameters_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Manage Parameters dialog box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Both MODFLOW-2005 style parameters and PEST parameters can be used with PEST. However, the way that PEST parameters are applied to data sets is somewhat different from how MODFLOW-2005 style parameters are applied. With MODFLOW-2005 style parameters for array data, the user can define zone and multiplier arrays. If a Zone array is used, the parameter will be applied to cells where the zone array data set is set to true. If a multiplier array is used, the value applied to a cell is the parameter value times the multiplier array value. It is possible to have more than one MODFLOW-2005 parameter to apply to the same cell of the same data set by setting the zone arrays for two or more parameters to true for the same cell. In that case, the value applied to the cell would be the sum of the values that would be applied by each parameter individually. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If PEST parameters are to be assigned to a data set, the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">PEST Parameters used</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> checkbox is checked on the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">PEST Parameters</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> tab of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Data_Sets_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Data Sets</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. The PEST parameters tab will only be present for some data sets. If it is not present, PEST parameters can not be used with that data set. ModelMuse only allows PEST parameters to be used with real-number data sets. It does not allow PEST parameters to be used with data sets that define the layer structure of the model despite those being real-number data sets. In addition in SUTRA models, parameters can only be applied to data sets corresponding to PMID, PMIN, ALMID, ALMIN, ATMID, AND ATMIN if anisotropy has not been selected for those data sets on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Anisotropy_Pane" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Anisotropy Pane</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="SUTRA_Options_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">SUTRA Options</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">For every data set for which the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">PEST Parameters used</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> checkbox is checked, a corresponding text data set will be created when the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Apply</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> button in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Data_Sets_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Data Sets</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box is clicked. The name of the corresponding data set will be the same as its parent data set with with "_Parameter_Names" appended. A PEST parameter will be applied to any cell in the parent data set for which the value of the _Parameter_Names data sets to the name of one of the PEST parameters. The </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Formula_Editor" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Formula Editor dialog box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> lists all the PEST parameters and these can be used as the formula for a _Parameter_Names data set either as the default formula in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Data_Sets_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Data Sets</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box or in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Data_Sets_Tab" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Data Sets Tab</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Object_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Object Properties dialog box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. When a PEST parameter is applied to a cell or element in a data set, the value at that cell or element is multiplied by the parameter value. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_"><text styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" translate="true">Using Pilot Points</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><snippet src="Pilot_Point_Explanation" /></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Candidate pilot point locations are defined in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Pilot_Points_P" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Pilot Points Pane</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST Properties dialog box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. They can be specified in several ways. They can occur in a regular pattern, be between point observations, be specified individually, or be any combination of these methods. The modeler also specifies a </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Pilot_Points_P" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">pilot point buffer</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> that affects how pilot points are defined.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Whether or not a particular parameter is associated with pilot points is specified ion the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Manage_Parameters_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Manage Parameters dialog box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. If pilot points are used with a parameter, the treatment of the parameter is somewhat modified while PEST is running. Instead of multiplying the data set value by the parameter value, each pilot point will be an independent parameter. The PEST utility program PLPROC will be used to interpolate among the pilot point values and the interpolated values will be assigned to the data set wherever the parent parameter is used. The pilot points used with a particular parameter for a particular data set will be any of the candidate pilot points defined on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Pilot_Points_P" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Pilot Points Pane</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST Properties dialog box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> that are no further away then the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Pest_Properties_Pilot_Points_P" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">pilot point buffer</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> from a cell center (MODFLOW) or node location or element center (SUTRA) that is part of the zone where the parameter applies. The initial value assigned to a pilot point will be the value at the data set in ModelMuse. However, if the parent parameter for a pilot point is not used for the pilot point location, the nearest location for which it is used will supply the initial value for the pilot point.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">To clarify matters, lets look at a simple model with 10 rows, 10 columns, and 1 layer. The rows and columns have a spacing of 100 meters. The model has two parameters defined - KLeft and KRight as illustrated below. They will be used to define the hydraulic conductivity in the X direction on the left and right sides of the model respectively. Both parameters have initial values of 1. Pilot points are used with KRight but not with KLeft. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="PestParamDefinition.png" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Screen capture of the Manage Parameters dialog box with two parameters defined.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Screen capture of the Manage Parameters dialog box with two parameters defined.]]></caption></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">There are 25 candidate pilot points defined that are spaced 200 meters apart as illustrated below. Nine of the pilot points are outside the model grid. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="ExampleCandidatePilotPoints.png" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Screen capture illustrating the locations of the candidate pilot points.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Screen capture illustrating the locations of the candidate pilot points.]]></caption></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The pilot point buffer in this model is 290 m. Because the leftmost column of pilot points is more than 290 meters from the center of any cell in the right half of the model (where pilot points are applied) that column of pilot points will not be used. On the other hand, the pilot points above and to the right of the grid (except the one in the first column) are within the pilot point buffer and will be used. Their initial values will come from the cell to which each of them is closest. In addition, the second column of candidate pilot points will be used because they are within 290 m of the left hand side of the model where the KRight parameter is applied. Their initial values will come from the nearest cell on the left-hand side of the model.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The model also has some boundary conditions and observations but those aren't described here.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">After PEST has finished running, the values assigned to the Kx data can be displayed using "File|Import|Gridded Data Files..." To do so, select the file containing the final values in the "arrays" subdirectory of the directory in which the model ran. The file will have the extension ".arrays." The final distribution of Kx is shown below. Note that the left half of the model where no pilot points were used has a uniform distribution of Kx values whereas in the right half where pilot points were used, the hydraulic conductivity varies among the cells.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="PestExamplePilotPoints.png" scale="-99.90%" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Diagram showing distribution of Kx values after PEST estimated parameters.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Diagram showing distribution of Kx values after PEST estimated parameters.]]></caption></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading3_atoc_"><text styleclass="Heading3_atoc_" translate="true">Important Caveat</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The formulas assigning values to data sets are only applied in ModelMuse. When PEST is running, those formulas are not used. This is especially important to keep in mind when a data set is related to a direction such as the Kx, Ky, and Kz data sets in MODFLOW.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">With MODFLOW models, having PEST assign values to the Kx data set does not mean that the Ky and Kz data sets will be automatically updated by PEST too. As far as PEST is concerned, those are completely unrelated items. For MODFLOW models, there are options to use horizontal and vertical anisotropy instead of directly specifying Ky and Kz. For MODFLOW 6, these are options in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="NPF_Node_Property_Flow_Package" anchor="K22OVERK" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Node Property Flow</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> package. For the LPF and UPW packages, horizontal anisotropy is used automatically but vertical anisotropy can be specified by an option on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Basics_Tab" anchor="VKA" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Basics Tab</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="MODFLOW_Layer_Groups_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">MODFLOW Layer Groups</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. For the BCF package, horizontal anisotropy is used automatically. Vertical leakance in the BCF package is a function of the vertical hydraulic conductivities of the more than one layer. In the HUF package, all data is specified using parameters. If you don't use pilot points, it wouldn't be difficult to tie one parameter to another in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Manage_Parameters_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Manage Parameters dialog box</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. You can also define parameters for horizontal and vertical anisotropy in the HUF package.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">With SUTRA models, having PEST assign values to the the dispersivity, permeability, or hydraulic conductivity in the "max" direction does not mean PEST will assign values in the "mid" or "min" directions unless anisotropy is used. ModelMuse allows you to use horizontal and vertical anisotropy for those data sets and anisotropy is used by default. The anisotropy options are specified on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Anisotropy_Pane" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Anisotropy Pane</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="SUTRA_Options_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">SUTRA Options</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
