<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Using Singlular Value Decomposition</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Using Singlular Value Decomposition</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If Singular Value Decomposition is to be used with PEST, you can use &quot;superparameters&quot; to reduce the PEST execution time. You can select </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">File|Export|PEST|Calculate Number of Super-Parameters</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> to display the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="SupCalc_Options_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">SUPCALC Options</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. With this option, ModelMuse will create a PEST Control File, and then use the SUPCALC PEST utility program to modify the PEST Control file. After running SUPCALC with the modified PEST file, it will restore the backed-up PEST control file. SUPCALC will display the minimum &#160;number of super-parameters to use with the model.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If the option to run PEST &#160;is selected, ModelMuse will back up the existing PEST control file and export a new one suitable for use with SUPCALC. Then ModelMuse will create a batch file named RunSupCalc.bat. The batch file will first run PEST if that option is selected and then restore the backed-up PEST control file. It will then add a command to run SUPCALC. If the option to run SUPCALC is selected, ModelMuse will start the RunSupCalc.bat batch file. SUPCALC will display the minimum number of super-parameters for the model.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Next, the user can select </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">File|Export|PEST|Modify PEST Control File with SVDAPREP</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> to display the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="SVDAPrep_Input_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">SVDAPREP Input</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. This dialog box will allow you to</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> generate a PEST control file suitable for use with Singular Value Decomposition by running the SVDAPREP PEST utility program and then run PEST with the modified PEST control file.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
