<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst-pr" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Using Objects to Specify the Mesh</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Using Objects to Specify the Mesh</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Using objects to specify a mesh is nearly the same as </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Using_Objects_to_Specify_the_G" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">using objects to specify a grid</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. However, when generating a mesh, only objects on the top view are used and you are allowed to use point objects as well as lines and polygons. To different methods can be used. The </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Irregular</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> algorithm used to generate the mesh is modified from the one described by Sarrate and Huerta (2000). Another option is to use the Gmsh program available from </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="http://geuz.org/gmsh/" target="_blank" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">http://geuz.org/gmsh/</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">To generate the mesh, the user creates one or more objects on the top view of the model. At least one of the objects must be a polygon. The object with the largest area will define the outer boundary of the mesh. Any polygons inside the outer boundary will be treated as holes in the mesh (blue lines, fig. 1). To define polygonal areas within the mesh that will not be holes inside the mesh, two or more polylines that cross each other can be used (red lines, fig. 1). With the </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Irregular</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> algorithm, edges of elements will lie along the polyline and polygon objects and there will be a node at point objects. The objects can intersect one another. With </text><text styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Gmsh</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">, point objects and the parts of polyline objects that can not be combined to form polygons will be ignored. For each object that will be used to help specify the mesh, the user checks the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Properties_Tab" anchor="GridElementSize" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Use to set mesh element size</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> check box in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Properties_Tab" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Object Properties</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box and enters a value for the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Properties_Tab" anchor="GridElementSize" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Mesh element size</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. For profile models, </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Properties_Tab" anchor="GridElementSize" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Mesh element size</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> refers to the size of the element in the X direction. The size of the element in the Y direction is the specified size divided by the vertical exaggeration. The user can override the mesh element size for individual vertices in an object by using the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Vertex_Values_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Vertex Values</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. Any vertex for which the key is set to &quot;Mesh Element Size&quot; will have it&apos;s element size set to the value specified. After the objects have been created, the user then selects </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Mesh|Generate Mesh...</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> or clicks the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Generate mesh</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> button </text><image src="GenerateGrid.png" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption"></image><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. The </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Mesh_Generation_Control_Variab" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Mesh Generation Control Variables</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box will appear. The user makes sure that the Mesh generation method is set to </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Irregular</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> and clicks OK to generate the mesh. The user should be aware that there will always be at least one SUTRA node in between any two verticies of an object used to constrain the mesh. The </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Mesh_Information_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Strong" translate="true">Mesh Information</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box displays statistics about the mesh.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="2" colcount="1">
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td>
          <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="HolesInMesh.png" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption"></image></para>
        </td>
      </tr>
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td>
          <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Image Number" translate="true">Figure</text><text styleclass="Image Caption" translate="true">. Example of using objects (colored lines) to define where the mesh should be located. The two blue, interior objects define holes in the mesh. The two red interior objects define areas of mesh refinement that are not holes in the mesh.</text></para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The mesh is generated using a domain decomposition approach. The objects used to define the mesh are joined into one or more polygons and nodes are placed along the polygons using the spacing specified by the user. The polygons are then split by selecting two nodes along the polygon and joining them. New nodes are added along the new edge as needed. This is continued until only polygons with four nodes are left. The positions of the nodes are then adjusted and some topological changes are made to improve the mesh quality.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">There are seven variables that help control how the mesh is generated. The first variable, </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Element growth rate</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">, controls the spacing of nodes when new nodes need to be placed along a line and different element spacings have been specified for the two ends of the line. The others control which nodes will be selected as the end points of a line that splits a polygon. When selecting the end points, each potential pair of end points is evaluated according to several criteria to assess which pair of end points is best. The control variables are used to weight each of these criteria in an overall assessment of the the pair of end points. A more detailed discussion of the control variables is presented below.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><snippet src="Mesh_Control_Variables"/></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The values Sarrate and Huerta (2000) suggested values for control variables are used as defaults in ModelMuse. For the other control variables (</text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Element growth rate </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:normal;" translate="true">and </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Concave</text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:normal;" translate="true">), numerical experiments were performed to identify appropriate default values. However, no single set of control values was ideal for every tested model. If the mesh generated with the default values is not satisfactory, the user may try varying any of the control variables. Sometimes a small change in a control variable results in a radically different final mesh.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
