<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" status="Under Construction" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Using PEST Parameters with Model Features</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Using PEST Parameters with Model Features</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Model features are used to define model inputs that have a spatial component but which do not necessarily apply to every cell, node or element in the model. Model features include boundary conditions such as wells in MODFLOW models or specified pressures in SUTRA. Some model features are not boundary conditions such as the Horizontal Flow Barriers in MODFLOW. Many, but not all, model features can vary with time. For model features that do not vary with time, you can specify a formula that is either a PEST parameter name or the name of a data set for which </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Data_Sets_Dialog_Box" anchor="PESTParameters" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST parameters are used</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. If the name of a PEST parameter is specified, the value of the PEST parameter will substituted into the model input file when PEST is estimating parameters. If the name of a data set whose value are modified by PEST, the updated value from the data set will substituted into the model input file.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In cases where there can be temporal variation in a model feature, the times and formulas for the model feature are shown in a table in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Object_Properties_Dialog_Box" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Object Properties</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. However, the top two rows of these tables are reserved for the PEST modifier and the modification method as illustrated below. The PEST modifier is optional. If the PEST modifier is specified, it must be either a PEST parameter or the name of a data set for which </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Data_Sets_Dialog_Box" anchor="PESTParameters" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST parameters are used</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"><image src="DrnBoundaryPEST.png" scale="60.00%" width="589" height="440" styleclass="Image Caption"><title translate="true">Screen capture of the Object Properties dialog box showing new rows for the PEST modifier and the modifiation method.</title><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Screen capture of the Object Properties dialog box showing new rows for the PEST modifier and the modifiation method.]]></caption></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The modification method determines how the PEST modifier is used. It must be either &quot;Add&quot; or &quot;Multiply&quot;. If it is &quot;Add&quot;, all the values for all the times will have the value from the PEST modifier added to them. If it is &quot;Multiply&quot;, all the values for all the times will be multiplied by the value from the PEST modifier. PEST modifiers are used when you want all the values for a particular feature to be varied in a coordinated fashion. The modification method is generally set to &quot;Add&quot; for elevation related items and to &quot;Multiply&quot; for all others.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If you want to use different parameters for different times, you can do so by using the name of a PEST parameter or a data set for which </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Data_Sets_Dialog_Box" anchor="PESTParameters" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">PEST parameters are used</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> as the formula for an individual time. When generating the input files for the model, the value of the PEST parameter or the value from the data set will be substituted into the input file. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">It is possible to use a formula for an individual time that is determined by a PEST parameter together with a PEST modifier. When generating the model input file, the value from the formula will be adjusted using the PEST modifier.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal" style="margin-left:0px;"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
