<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Popup" lasteditedby="rbwinst-pr" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">FMTIN</title>
  <body>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">FMTIN—is the format for reading array elements. The format must contain 20 characters or less. The format must either be a standard Fortran format that is enclosed in parentheses, &quot;(FREE)&quot; which indicates free format, or &quot;(BINARY)&quot; which indicates binary (unformatted) data. When using a free-format control record, the format must be enclosed in apostrophes if it contains one or more blanks or commas. There are only two ways to create a binary file that can be read by MODFLOW. The first way is to use MODFLOW to create the file by saving heads in a binary file. This is commonly done when it is desired to use computed heads from one simulation as initial heads for a subsequent simulation. The other way to create a binary file is to write a special program that generates a binary file. &quot;(FREE)&quot; and &quot;(BINARY)&quot; can only be specified in free-format control records. Also, &quot;(BINARY)&quot; can only be specified when using U2DREL or U2DINT, and only when the control record is </text><text styleclass="Keywords" translate="true">EXTERNAL</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> or </text><text styleclass="Keywords" translate="true">OPEN/CLOSE</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">. When the &quot;(FREE)&quot; option is used, be sure that all array elements have a non-blank value and that a comma or at least one blank separates adjacent values.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="New Materials" translate="true">When using FREE format, the data for each of the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="DIS" anchor="NROW" styleclass="New Materials" translate="true">NROW</link><text styleclass="New Materials" translate="true"> rows needs to start on a new line.</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
