<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic class="popup" template="Popup" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Node/Subreach Records.</title>
  <body>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">I, X, IOUT, F, A1, A2, A0, SL, W1, and W2 - The node records define the node number, location of the node in miles or kilometers, an output flag, for each node and the initial flow, hydraulic-geometry parameters and slope for each subreach. The hydraulic-geometry exponents are independent of the system of units, but the hydraulic-geometry coefficients are dependent upon the units used. The number of node-records input must equal the number specified on the branch record. Node records are input in sequence starting with the node 1, at the upstream end of the branch. The node location is specified as the distance to the cross section from a reference point at or above the upstream end of the branch. The initial discharge, slope, and all coefficients apply to the subreach extending from the node for which it is specified to the next node downstream. For example, the value of A1 input for node 1 applies to the subreach extending from node 1 to node 2. Because there is no subreach downstream of the last node, only the river mile and output flag needs to be specified for the last node. The model is based on the assumption that tributaries enter the stream just upstream of the node. The initial discharge for subreach I, therefore, should include the effect of the tributary flow at node I. The output flag (IOUT) specifies whether or not the flow information for the node is to be printed in the output file. The data at each node is read as a free-field format, so it is not necessary to keep the numbers in any particular column or even to line them up. It is necessary that at least one blank space separate each number and that a number be available for each variable. Exponential formats (see slope) are acceptable. The formats shown in Table 1 are used if the file is created interactively using the program BDAFLOW (Jobson, 1989).</text></para>
  </body>
</topic>
