<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst-pr" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Archive Structure</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Archive Structure</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The purpose of the </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Archive Structure</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> pane is to add or remove files from the archive and to assign descriptions to files and folders. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The description assigned to the selected item in the archive is displayed in an edit box below the archive structure. The user should provide descriptions for any items that lack them. Default descriptions will be assigned to items based on the file extensions assigned in the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="File_Extensions_Form" styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">File Extensions</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box. The descriptions will be used to update the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Readme.txt_File" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">readme.txt</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> file and </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Metadata" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">metadata</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> files when the archive is created.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Archive Structure</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> pane shows all the files to be included in the archive arranged in the folder structure that will be used in the archive. This pane can be used to add or remove individual files, to move them from one place to another in the archive structure, or to make other changes to the archive structure. The archive structure pane is also where the descriptions of individual items are assigned. To make changes in what files are included in the archive structure, click on the archive structure at the location where you wish to make a change, right-click with the mouse, and select the desired option from the pop-up menu. For example, you could add or delete files or folders. To edit the description of an item, select the item and enter the description in the edit box labeled “Item Description.” The user can also drag files from Windows Explorer to add them to the archive structure. If a file has been placed in the wrong folder, it can be moved by either dragging it to the correct folder or by using a copy and paste operation in the archive structure similar to how files can be moved between folders in Windows Explorer.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelArchiver uses color to highlight problems in the model archive (see figure below) or to highlight files from archive lists that will not be included in the final archive. Three colors are used to indicate problems: red, yellow, and blue. If a problem is identified in any of the items in the archive structure, that item and all its parent items will be drawn with a colored background. A red background indicates the file does not exist at the location where it was specified to exist. In the figure below, no readme.txt file has been specified. A yellow background indicates that no description has been supplied for the item. In the figure below, no descriptions have been supplied for the Model1, Model2 or Model6_MODPATH folders in the output directory directory. A blue background indicates that another file with the same name is in the same folder of the archive structure. In the figure below, MP6_Test1.mpn and MP6_Test1.mpn.archive are treated as duplicate names. Duplicate names can occur for two reasons. (1) The file names are identical except that one has the extension &quot;.archive&quot;. (As explained </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="File_Extensions" anchor="ArchiveExtension" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">earlier</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">, the &quot;.archive&quot; extension will be removed when the archive is created.) (2) The file names are the same but the files are in different directories on the computer. If more than one problem exists for an item, the color will be a mixture of the above colors. The model and output in the figure below directories show examples of color mixtures due to multiple problems.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If a file was added to the archive structure by virtue of being included in an archive list, the file will not be removed from the archive structure if the user attempts to delete it. Instead, it will be marked as a file not to include in the archive and will be colored with a dark gray background. The MP6_Test.gpt file in the ancillary directory illustrates a file from the archive list that has been deleted from the archive. It might be desirable to delete files listed in an archive list if they have been moved to another location on the computer or are no longer available.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="ArchiveStructure.png" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Archive Structure Pane in ModelArchiver illustrating the use of color to highlight problems in the archive or deleted files.]]></caption></image></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><snippet src="Update_Paths"/></para>
  </body>
</topic>
