<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst-pr" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Edit Metadata Dialog Box</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Edit Metadata Dialog Box</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The </text><text styleclass="Normal" style="font-weight:bold;" translate="true">Edit Metadata</text><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> dialog box is built using the same source code as FGDCMetaEditor so they have the same functionality except for how metadata files are opened and saved. In ModelArchiver, files are opened by selecting the &quot;Edit metadata file&quot; button on the </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="Metadata" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Metadata</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true"> pane of the ModelArchiver main form. The metadata file is saved by clicking the &quot;Save and Close&quot; button. </text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The left side of the editor is a tree control that includes the names and numbers of the standard tags in FGDC metadata. Each item has either a checkbox or radiobutton associated with it. If the checkbox or radiobutton is checked and all its parent items are also checked, the associated item will be included in the metadata file. If an item is required, the checkbox will be disabled so that the user can not uncheck it. When the user selects an item, the right hand side shows a description of the item and provides a way to edit that item (see figure below). If an item will be included in the metadata file but has not been specified, its name is colored with a blue background on the left hand side (see figure below). If the FGDC standard requires the metadata to specify one of several options, and none of those options have been selected, items are colored with a yellow background on the left hand side (see figure below). If the user has specified an invalid value for an option, its name is colored with a red background on the left hand side. If multiple copies of an item can be included in the metadata file, the item will have a blue “plus” symbol in front of its name. Clicking on the blue “plus” symbol or selecting it and clicking the “Duplicate” button will add a new copy of the item. If a metadata file is opened that includes items that are not part of the FGDC standard, the values for those items will be editable as text in the editor. However, the editor does not allow the user to add items to the metadata file that are not part of the FGDC standard and are not already in the metadata file.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Clicking the &quot;Search&quot; button allows the user to search the metadata for text in the text, description or name of each item in the metadata.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><image src="MetaDataEditorFig3.png" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Image Caption"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[FgdcMetaEditor showing the use of color to indicate missing data.]]></caption></image></para>
  </body>
</topic>
