<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Overview</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Overview</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelArchiver is a program to create groundwater model archives in the format specified by the USGS Office of Groundwater (OGW) Technical Memorandum No. 2016.02 (</text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="https://water.usgs.gov/admin/memo/GW/gw2016.02.pdf" target="_blank" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">https://water.usgs.gov/admin/memo/GW/gw2016.02.pdf</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">). More details about the required archive format are at </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="weblink" href="https://water.usgs.gov/ogw/policy/gw-model/" target="_blank" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">https://water.usgs.gov/ogw/policy/gw-model/</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelArchiver can lead the user step-by-step through the process of setting up the archive. However, the user can also skip any of the steps and come back to them later if desired. The most basic part of the model archive is the input and output files of the model or models. In addition there are a number of additional files that provide information about the models such as the geographic location of the model area. ModelArchiver lets the user select these files. When all the files have been selected, it transfers them to the archive directory and compresses some of them as described in the policy.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelArchiver allows you to select individual model files to add to the archive or select a directory. ModelArchiver can use file extensions to help determine what files to include in an archive, whether they are input or output files, and provide a brief default description of the purpose of each file. ModelArchiver can also select &quot;archive lists&quot; for individual model. Each archive list includes information about the files to include in the archive for a specific model. Archive lists can be generated by ModelMuse (Winston, 2009, 2014) for use with ModelArchiver. More information about the structure of archive lists is in </text><link displaytype="text" defaultstyle="true" type="topiclink" href="File_Lists_and_ModelMuse_Integ" styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Archive Lists and ModelMuse Integration</link><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">.</text></para>
    <para styleclass="Normal"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
