<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2022-06-08T17:08:40.911-04:00" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Version 5.0</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Version 5.0</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="true" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading2_atoc_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Version 5.0 March 18, 2022]]></caption></toggle></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="true" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Enhancements]]></caption></toggle></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
            <tr style="vertical-align:top">
              <td>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added support for PEST with MODFLOW and SUTRA models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The user can now customize ModelMuse to specify whether or not a model archive will be created.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added new function MaxSutraNodeValueInElement</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added the functions ObjectVerticalLength and ObjectVerticalIntersectLength.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added support for importing Lake for the MODFLOW 6 Lake package from Shapefiles.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In the Rearrange Objects dialog box, it is now possible to specify the order of objects by entering a new position in a new third column in the grid.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse can now read concentration files generated by MODFLOW 6.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added a &quot;Deselect&quot; option to the popup menu in the Show or Hide Objects dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When contouring a data set in a MODFLOW-LGR model, the user can now choose which models should be contoured on the filter tab of the contour pane of the Data Visualization dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse now checks for MNW2 well screens that are below the bottom of the grid.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Allow the user to choose how to assign gridded data when importing existing MODFLOW models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added support for features in RCT package in MT3D-USGS that are not in MT3DMS.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing an existing model, imported arrays for transient data now include the stress period as part of the comment.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In the Show or Hide Objects dialog box, double-clicking on a category heading will expand or collapse that category.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added some error checking when exporting the MAW input file.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When exporting MT3D and MODPATH files, ModelMuse issues an error message if the porosity is less than or equal to zero in any active cell.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The initial dialog box now appears on the taskbar.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Adaptive time stepping in MODFLOW 6 is supported.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added new functions HGU_HK, HGU_HANI, HGU_VK, HGU_VANI, HGU_SS, HGU_SY, and HGU_KDEP which return the value of the corresponding data for a particular hydrogeologic unit.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added new function GetValueFromLayer that allows a 2D data set to retrieve a value from a specific layer of a 3D data set.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When writing the reservoir layer, ModelMuse now checks for invalid layer numbers and layers that are beneath non-simulated layers.</text></para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="false" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Changes]]></caption></toggle></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
            <tr style="vertical-align:top">
              <td>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse now creates a file named &quot;usgs.model.reference.&quot; for the groundwater flow model. Previously, the &quot;model&quot; part of the file name would be the name of the model. A file with the model name as part of the file name is still created. &quot;Usgs.model.reference&quot; is used for model archives. If multiple models are in the same directory, the duplicate with the &quot;model&quot; replaced by the name of the model can be used to create a new copy of &quot;usgs.model.reference&quot; for the desired model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">File extension for the Reservoir package input file change from &quot;.res&quot; to &quot;.resv&quot; to avoid conflict with a PEST output file.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When reading pathline, endpoint, or time-series files from MODPATH 7, ModelMuse will skip lines that contain NaN instead of numbers and displays an error message.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse now creates backups of several files such as the RunModel file for use in tests of ModelMuse.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Changed the formula for the initial head in MODFLOW models to Model_Top.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse no longer includes RCH, EVT, or ETS among the point sources in MT3D-USGS in non MODFLOW 6 models.</text></para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="false" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Bug fixes]]></caption></toggle></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
            <tr style="vertical-align:top">
              <td>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If no MODFLOW stress periods are defined when the user attempts to generate the MODFLOW input files, one will now be created automatically.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">It is no longer possible to define two parameters with the same name in the Manage Parameters dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an access violation when drawing contours with a MODFLOW DISV model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In some cases where a circular reference error would have resulted in a bug report, a message to the user will be displayed instead.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in importing specific storage from the BCF package when importing an existing MODFLOW-2005 or MODFLOW-NWT model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause a range-check error when drawing contours if the cross section does not intersect the mesh.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause a bug report to be generated when opening an existing model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed defining CSUB observations for csub, inelastic-csub, elastic-csub, sk, ske, interbed-compaction, inelastic-compaction, elastic-compaction, and thickness observation types.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed import of the MODFLOW-2005 lake package in models with only one layer.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed the ^ operator so that it will accept two real-number arguments.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in the Manage Head Observations dialog box when the user clicked the Highlight Selected Object button without first selecting any objects in the table.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse now creates UCN file in MT3D-USGS for the sorbed phase when the sorbtion choice is linear.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse no longer generates a bug report if the user specifies more than one contour value for a boolean data set.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When writing real number array values, real numbers close to zero will be written as zero if they require more precision than is provided by a single precision real number.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an assertion failure when accessing vertex values.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause access violations when evaluating the RCH or ETS packages after disabling MODFLOW 6 observations.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When drawing a fishnet mesh, it is no longer possible to add the same node to a fishnet mesh element twice.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause range check error if exporting an image of a 2D data set and restoring the image settings from the saved settings.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug so that in MODLFOW 6 lakes the lake bottom elevation is never too low and the lake top elevation is never too high in horizontal lake connections.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse can now display vectors for MODFLOW 6 models in the Export Image dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that would cause an error when importing data in the Import Points dialog box if the decimal separator was not a period.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When attempting to read or save a global variables file, ModelMuse will now show an error message to the user instead of issuing a bug report if there is an error reading the file.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause ModelMuse to encounter an error when evaluating the IDOMAIN data set in MODFLOW 6 models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing UZF data from shapefiles in models in which the UZT package is active, UZT will also be imported.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause WellFootprint models to fail when exporting withdrawals.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause a range check error when deleting an item in the SWR Range Geometry dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If the user attempts to edit CSUB data for an object without first defining any interbeds, ModelMuse will display a warning message for the user instead of generating a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that prevented the functions for identifying the highest active layer from working with DISV MODFLOW 6 models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause access violations if a formula started with a comma.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause access violations when shutting down ModelMuse.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When moving vertices of an object to the location of a vertex in another object, there could be a slight error in the location to which the vertex was moved. This has been corrected.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation when opening a model if the model that is already open had contours displayed or a data set used to color the grid or mesh.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an error when exporting SUTRA model if no time schedule has been defined.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed import of multiple ASCII grid files simultaneously.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in export of Shapefile mesh data from SUTRA 2D models that could cause a range check error.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug in the Errors and Warnings dialog box that could cause an Invalid class typecast error when right clicking in the dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an assertion failure when working with the Object Properties dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation in the SUTRA Time Controls dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation in the Manage Parameters dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug with renaming MODFLOW parameters when the only change was a change in the capitalization of the parameter name.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that caused an access violation when pasting data from one model to another.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed setting default exaggeration with SUTRA 2D models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug in exporting the Basic Package input file in models that contain nonsimulated layers.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of MAW package when flowing wells were used.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation in the Export Image dialog box if the user attempts to generate a side view image of a MODFLOW 6 DISV model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in export of MAW package input that could cause MODFLOW 6 to stop with an error message for inactive wells.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If an SWR Reach boundary did not define data for some stress periods, ModelMuse now defines inactive reaches for those stress periods.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in drawing contours that could cause a range check error.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If there is an out of memory error when drawing the 3D view, the 3D view will be hidden until ModelMuse is restarted.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug pasting objects from the clipboard when the clipboard can not be accessed.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an error when exporting data to a CSV file.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing data from a file, ModelMuse now only allows you to specify files that actually exist.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation when exporting the ETS package if EVT depth or rate fractions have not been assigned.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In the Geo Reference dialog box, the model start date now displays the format for dates used in the computer in which the starting date is being edited.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that caused panning the model or resizing the main form to be unnecessarily slow.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that would cause a bug report to be generated if the Used item of a SUTRA boundary condition did not evaluate to true or false. Now an error message is displayed.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In MODFLOW 6 models, including lines for the RCH or EVT packages in the MODFLOW Name File dialog box will now prevent ModelMuse from exporting the input files for those packages.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in coloring the grid with a data set in a MODFLOW-LGR model that could cause a circular reference error.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause MODFLOW 6 observation files to be misnamed if the model file name had a period within the base as well as one separating the base from the extension.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation when closing a MODFLOW LGR model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug in the &quot;File|Import|Grid Data Files&quot; dialog box in which the &quot;Open files&quot; button did not work unless more than one file was selected.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in exporting the UZF input in MODFLOW 6 that caused the convergence history file to be misnamed.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in implementation of the K22OVERK and K33OVERK options in the NPF package.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause some cells to be incorrectly selected two or more times by the same object when the object selects both enclosed and intersected cells.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that prevented MT3D concentration results from being imported.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in deleting Subsidence-related interbeds.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation if the name of a global variable that was used in a model feature was changed.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug moving the first vertex of a closed object section.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an assertion failure when writing the UZF file in MODFLOW 6.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that would cause an access violation if the UZF package in MODFLOW-2005 was converted to the UZF package in MODFLOW 6 and the model was exported without saving and closing the model first.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause a range check error if an object defining a stream in the MODFLOW 6 SFR package did not intersect any cells.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed check for connectivity in DISV grids in MODFLOW 6.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug with exporting MVR package.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in importing Shapefiles if unnamed CSV attributes are included.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed reading TProgs binary data files containing byte-sized integer data.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an exception to be raised in models with large grids.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse will now correct the data type, orientation, and where the data set is evaluated for any required data set if those values are incorrect.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse will no longer attempt to export MNWI model input files in MODFLOW 6 models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed display of MODPATH output in MODFLOW DISV models in which the cross section angle is not zero.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in resetting velocity vectors to not used.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause MODFLOW stress period starting and ending times to be saved with small rounding errors.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in displaying contour values.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed renaming of data sets associated with MODFLOW parameters when the parameters are renamed.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug in exporting SUTRA time schedules for BCS files in which the time steps were one greater than they should have been.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug importing SUTRA BCOF, BCOP, BCOS, and BCOU files in which inactive boundaries were not handled correctly.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause errors when exporting files if object names were not unique.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause ModelMuse to enter an infinite loop when using triangle interpolation.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If a MODFLOW 6 Lake outlet has no transient data assigned, ModelMuse now issues an error message instead of failing.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that would cause MODFLOW 6 MVR receivers to sometimes not be found if the receiver was a lake.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed assigning values to nodes or elements in SUTRA and cells in MODFLOW 6 DISV models when both intersected and enclosed items are to be assigned values when there are two elevation formulas.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed saving CREFT in SUTRA models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug where the LakeID was not set properly.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed the ability to define recharge solute flux observations in MT3D.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Attempting to insert a new layer group when more than one layer group is selected no longer causes an access violation.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Changing the layer size multiplier in the MODFLOW Layer Groups dialog box now causes DISV grids to be updated correctly.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed the display of a warning message while exporting Shapefiles.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of Zonebudget files for archive.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause the lake package in MODFLOW 6 to be created incorrectly if the lake only had vertical connections.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed the Import Gridded Data dialog box so that it no longer automatically changes the number of ignored values to 1 when a data set is selected.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The specify Contours dialog box no longer allows the users to attempt to set the number of contours to a value less than 1.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause extra LPF or HUF parameters to be generated when switching among parameter types in the MODFLOW Packages and Programs dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an assertion failures when importing shapefiles data from CSV files, if one or more columns did not have column headers.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of SFT when no SFT boundaries are defined.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of SFT package in MT3D-USGS when there is more than one chemical species.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that caused an access violation if the InterpolatedVertexValues function was used without an &#160;argument.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed display of XT3D data in the Grid or Mesh Values dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When saving the MODFLOW Name file, the Byte Order Mark should no longer be written.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an error when merging objects.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause incorrect values to be exported when exporting contours to Shapefiles.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of SSM in MT3D-USGS when the DRT package is used.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed evaluation of node outlines in the front view of 3D SUTRA models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that resulted in an invalid SUTRA fishnet mesh when the &quot;increase backwards&quot; option was used.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could result in Assertion failures when creating BCS files.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that resulted in an invalid SUTRA fishnet mesh when the &quot;increase forward&quot; option was used.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of MT3D-USGS lake transport package for models with more than one chemical species.</text></para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table></para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
