<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2022-03-18T06:17:47.177-04:00" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Version 3.3</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Version 3.3</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="true" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading2_atoc_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Version 3.3.0 Oct. 17, 2014]]></caption></toggle></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="true" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Enhancements]]></caption></toggle></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
            <tr style="vertical-align:top">
              <td>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added support for the Surface Water Routing process (SWR).</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing model results for a MODFLOW model, it is now possible to select all the data of a certain type or a certain time step by checking a single check box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When displaying data or head observation results, the root mean square residual is displayed in the Data Visualization dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In the Show and Hide Objects, dialog box, the head observation group name is displayed with head observations.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing model results from MODFLOW-LGR2 models, ModelMuse now does a better job of selecting default names for the model result files for the child models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">VertexValue function added.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added a method for importing multiple gridded data files at one time.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added the capability to import quadrilateral meshes generated by Argus ONE for use in SUTRA.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added ability to display labels with objects.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added a plot of simulated versus observed values for head observation results.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Creating contour plots of SUTRA data is faster.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Improved speed of displaying object properties for SUTRA models in the Object Properties dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added support for importing model results data from .bcof, .bcos, .bcop, or .bcou SUTRA output files into ModelMuse.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing existing MODFLOW models that have invalid tributary numbers in the STR package, ModelMuse now generates a warning message to the user instead of a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If there is an error importing and existing MODFLOW model, the error message dialog box will show the console lines generated by MODFLOW importing program as an aid to diagnosing the problem.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Improved checking of layer heights in MODFLOW models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The Global variables dialog box has been converted to a non-modal dialog box.</text></para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="false" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Changes]]></caption></toggle></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
            <tr style="vertical-align:top">
              <td>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The formula used for 3D data sets when importing model results has been changed;</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In MODFLOW-LGR and MODFLOW-LGR2 models, child models are now only displayed on the front and side views if the selected row or column of the parent model intersects the child model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse no longer checks for certain discrepancies in the SFR package input files when importing existing models. The change allows such models to be imported for the purpose of visualizing them. However, it will not be possible to run such models from ModelMuse until the discrepancies are resolved.</text></para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="false" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Bug fixes]]></caption></toggle></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
            <tr style="vertical-align:top">
              <td>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in determining tributaries in the STR package.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed display of transient data when the specified time is the first time in a stress period.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">fixed bug that could cause ModelMuse to enter an infinite loop when using the ACM 626 method to draw contour lines.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse can now handle a data set that has an invalid formula when first opening the model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug importing MODFLOW models containing specified heads defined by both the CHD package and negative IBOUND values.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bugs related to editing and exporting CFP information.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug the could cause and access violation when switching to a SUTRA model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed generation of time schedules in SUTRA when one or more of the times is larger than the largest possible single precision number.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of time information for MT3DMS.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of MODFLOW flow observation factors when the formula for the factor uses the layer, row, or column number.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Entering an invalid maximum or minimum value to display in the Data Visualization dialog box no longer results in a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed importing model results with MODFLOW-LGR and MODFLOW-LGR2 models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If a formula for the pumping rate in a MODFLOW well results in a math error such as a division by zero error, An error message is displayed in the Errors and Warnings dialog box instead of generating a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse now saves the location of MODFLOW-LGR2.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug related to editing data for conduit recharge.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed the process of deleting and undoing the deletion of child models in MODFLOW-LGR and MODFLOW-LGR2.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed reading Shapefiles with 32-bit version of ModelMuse. (Not broken in 64-bit version.)</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In the Global Variables dialog box, clicking where there isn&apos;t a cell, no longer causes an error.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed drawing fishnet mesh elements in SUTRA models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed drawing objects in 2D SUTRA models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of FHB package input file when only flows or only heads were specified in the package.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed specification of FHB flow and head values to allow formulas to be used for the flows or heads.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed import of models in which routing to steams or lakes is defined in the UZF package but the lake and SFR packages are not active.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">fixed a bug that incorrectly prevented the deletion of selected points from complicated polygon objects.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed import of MODFLOW models containing the SFR input files that use external flow files.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed visualization of boundary conditions in SUTRA models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In some cases creating a contour plot of SUTRA data caused ModelMuse to crash.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed display of vectors in SUTRA.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed generation of error message is an invalid formula is used with SUTRA boundary conditions.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Cross sections no longer plot heads equal to HDRY in MODFLOW models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed vertical exaggeration in top view when switching from a SUTRA profile model to any other sort of model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed range check error when editing SUTRA boundary conditions.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an assertion failure when assigning values to a data set.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Attempting to export a Shapefile when the database file is in use, now results in an error message to the user instead of a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause a range check error in SUTRA models with large numbers of nodes.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Attempting to import a locked Shapefile now results in an error message to the user rather than a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing existing models, cell top and bottom elevations are now imported correctly.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Importing stream observations from existing models now works correctly when the same segment is part of more than one observation.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed editing of SFR channel data when a cross section was not required.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in importing existing models with multilayer head observations.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause ModelMuse to crash because of a stack overflow.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause a stack overflow when closing ModelMuse.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Sometimes it is impossible to save a very large model as a ModelMuse text file (.gpt). Now, if an error occurs in converting the file from the binary to the text format, the user is prompted to save the file as a binary file.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Output files from MODPATH version 5 are now archived.</text></para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table></para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
