<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<?xml-stylesheet type="text/xsl" href="../helpproject.xsl" ?>
<topic template="Default" modified="2022-03-18T06:14:23.839-04:00" lasteditedby="rbwinst" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:noNamespaceSchemaLocation="../helpproject.xsd">
  <title translate="true">Versions 4.3</title>
  <body>
    <header>
      <para styleclass="Heading1"><text styleclass="Heading1" translate="true">Versions 4.3</text></para>
    </header>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="true" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading2_atoc_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Version 4.3 Aug. 16, 2020]]></caption></toggle></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
      <tr style="vertical-align:top">
        <td>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="true" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Enhancements]]></caption></toggle></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
            <tr style="vertical-align:top">
              <td>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added support for CSUB package in MODFLOW 6.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added &quot;Object|Edit|Anonymize Selected Point Objects command.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse now uses less memory when importing existing models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Custom color schemes can now be used when plotting MODPATH data.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing an existing model that uses the BCF package, specific storage is calculated from the confined storage coefficient and hydraulic conductivity is calculated from transmissivity.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse now warns the user if any specified head cells are cells for which Kx, Ky, and Kz are all zero.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse now prints the number of active cells in a MODFLOW model as a comment either in the Basic package input file for pre-MODFLOW6 models or in the DIS or DISV files in MODFLOW 6 models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added new function: HighestActiveLayer. It returns the highest layer at a particular location that is active.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In 3D SUTRA models, there is a new data set named Active_Node. Setting that data set to False at any node makes the node inactive.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Added SUTRA_MeshEdgeNode function.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In MT3DMS models, ISSGOUT is now specified if the MNW1 package is active. In MT3D-USGS models, ISSGOUT is now specified if the MNW1 or MNW2 packages are active. The output file will have the extension .mt_mnw_out.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse can now display specific discharge vectors for MODFLOW 6 models.</text></para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="false" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Changes]]></caption></toggle></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
            <tr style="vertical-align:top">
              <td>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The NEWTON and UNDER_RELAXATION options in MODFLOW 6 can now be specified in the MODFLOW Packages and Programs dialog box as well as the MODFLOW Options dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Modified export of the MODFLOW-2005 Lake package input to allow for periods in which no lakes are active.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">With MODFLOW 6 observations, a prefix is added before each observation name to ensure that all the observation names are unique.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">ModelMuse no longer produces times series files for parameters. Instead, parameter values are incorporated into the values in the package input file.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">The ActiveOnLayer function was changed for MODFLOW 6 models to return True in the IDOMAIN data set is greater than 0.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When exporting a MODFLOW-OWHM model containing parameters, the user is given the opportunity to turn off printing cell lists.</text></para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><image src="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" scale="100.00%" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" figurelistinclude="0"></image><tab /><toggle type="dropdown" print-expanded="true" help-expanded="false" defaultstyle="true" translate="true" src-collapsed="hmtoggle_plus0.gif" src-expanded="hmtoggle_plus1.gif" styleclass="Heading3_atocs_"><caption translate="true"><![CDATA[Bug fixes]]></caption></toggle></para>
          <para styleclass="Heading3_atocs_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"><table styleclass="Default" rowcount="1" colcount="1">
            <tr style="vertical-align:top">
              <td>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When converting MNW2 wells to MAW wells, the SKIN option in MNW2 is now converted to the CUMULATIVE option in MAW instead of the SKIN option in MAW.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause issues with evaluating formulas that involve only integers.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that caused an assertion failure if MODFLOW 6 SFR streams were not assigned for every stress period.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed position of buttons for no-delay beds in the MODFLOW Layers dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed position of buttons for the SF6, MAW, and MT3D SSM packages in the Object Properties dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause a bug report to create when attempting to export an object to a Shapefile.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing a Shapefile, ModelMuse gives the option to convert from decimal degrees to UTM coordinates. However, this may result in an invalid operation if the actual coordinates are not in decimal degrees. ModelMuse now displays an error message rather than sending a bug report in such cases.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an assertion failure if an object that defined a MAW well was in a cell that was inactive in the top layer.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed display of pump capacity table in the MNW2 package.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause a range check error when using the UZF package in MODFLOW 6.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If ModelMuse encounters and error when trying to back up an initialization file, it no longer generates a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause range check errors when editing MNW2 wells.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug importing an existing MODFLOW model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed editing of stream gages.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in opening ModelMuse file for WellFootprint models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in saving ModelMuse file for WellFootprint models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that allowed the user to import Shapefiles that directly set the withdrawal rate in WellFootprint models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that allowed the user to import points that directly set the withdrawal rate in WellFootprint models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause the model selection to be set to the wrong value when creating a new model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause ModelMuse to have an Input/Output error when importing a model.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause importing points to fail if the values being imported had extra spaces before or after any value.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If the user attempts to plot a MODPATH, pathline, end-point, or time-series file that contains invalid layer numbers, ModelMuse will display an error message instead of generating a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could make it impossible to open a ModelMuse file.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed using binary head file for initial heads in MODFLOW 6.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When converting to MODFLOW 6 from earlier versions of MODFLOW the user can now convert the FHB package to the CHD and WEL packages.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When converting to MODFLOW 6 from a model in which the NWt package is selected, the Newton option in MODFLOW 6 is now selected automatically.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed using binary head file in MODFLOW 6 for starting heads.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of &quot;NO_PTC&quot; option in MODFLOW 6.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that caused an error if the user attempted to rename a layer group with an invalid name.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an error when drawing contours.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an assertion failure when drawing contours using the ACM 626 method.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed but that cause a conversion error if the user failed to specify the properties of a lake outlet correctly.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation when updating the legend for the colors displayed in the Data Visualization dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation in the Global Variables dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that resulted in a bug report being generated if ModelMuse attempted to import SUTRA results containing &quot;NaN&quot;.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of SUTRA data sets 21A and 21B when they are inactive initially.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that caused issues with opening files that contained very large or very small real number values.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an assertion failure when exporting SUTRA models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug in inserting or deleting well screens in the MNW2 package.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When importing Shapefiles that contained measured values, values less than -1E38 are treated as no-data values.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an assertion failure &#160;if identical starting and ending times were specified for the RCH package.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in reading binary MT3D model results that could cause a bug report to be generated.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in inserting a new composite zone for Zone Budget in the &quot;Model|MODFLOW Packages and Programs&quot; dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When exporting MT3D model input files, ModelMuse will now check whether any .ucn files that will be created by the model already exist. If they do exist, ModelMuse will delete them.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause an access violation when manually specifying the SUTRA mesh.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause the MAW observations to be written incorrectly.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">It is now possible to inactivate a STR boundary by deleting all the times at which the boundary is defined.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed export of grid data to Shapefile with DISV grids. Formerly, the cells boundaries could be exported in counterclockwise direction instead of clockwise direction.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed drawing active area outline to avoid access violations.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Changing the times of the MODFLOW Stress periods will now result in the times of MNW2 wells being updated to the same times.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">In MODFLOW 6 models, the CHD ending head can no longer be specified without using a parameter.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When converting to a MODFLOW 6 model, CHD boundaries that don&apos;t use parametes are converted to CHD boundaries that use a parameter.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When attempting to read an invalid .nod or .ele SUTRA output file, ModelMuse will now generate an error message for the user instead of issuing &#160;a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When attempting to read an invalid MODPATH output file, ModelMuse will now generate an error message for the user instead of issuing &#160;a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause objects to fail to intersect all the correct cells in MODFLOW DISV models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an assertion failure if recharge or evapotranspiration was used in some of the stress periods but not in others.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">With MODFLOW 6 models in which the &quot;Top Active Cell&quot; option in the Recharge and Evapotransipiration packages is selected, ModelMuse will automatically specify the layer as the top active layer at a particular location.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in export of the MODFLOW-2005 Lake package input file that could prevent data set 9 from being written for some stress periods after the first stress period.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an access violation when displaying the Object Properties dialog box.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Corrected spelling of CUPBGO in the Object Properties dialog box the the SUTRA Generalized Flow Boundary</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed allowing multiple &quot;Used&quot; formulas to be edited at once for SUTRA boundaries.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed &quot;Navigation|Go To&quot; dialog box to work more easily with SUTRA 2D models.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug that could cause assertion failures when exporting boundary conditions in SUTRA.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause the UZF input file to be created incorrectly.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed bug in animating contours.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">If the user attempts to import a mesh that is not in the correct format, ModelMuse now displays an appropriate error message instead of generating a bug report.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">When creating a new MODFLOW model, the user specified length and time units were not applied if the user clicked the &quot;No Grid&quot; button.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause an invalid warning to be issued about transient SFR items with a duration of zero.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Changing a time in the MODFLOW Time dialog box now causes corresponding times defined for SFR package to be updated.</text></para>
                <para styleclass="Normal"><text styleclass="Normal" translate="true">Fixed a bug that could cause some formulas to fail if a data set is renamed.</text></para>
              </td>
            </tr>
          </table></para>
        </td>
      </tr>
    </table></para>
    <para styleclass="Heading2_atoc_" style="text-indent:-18px; margin-left:18px;"></para>
  </body>
</topic>
